<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A discourse of money Being an essay on that subject, historically and politically handled. With reflections on the present evil state of the coin of this kingdom; and proposals of a method for the remedy. In a letter to a nobleman, &amp;c.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1696</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 153 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 113 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A81515</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing D1600A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R213093</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99825603</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99825603</idno>
            <idno type="VID">132772-01</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A81515)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 132772-01)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1791:2, 2512:7)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A discourse of money Being an essay on that subject, historically and politically handled. With reflections on the present evil state of the coin of this kingdom; and proposals of a method for the remedy. In a letter to a nobleman, &amp;c.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[4], 192, 183-198, 197-204 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for Sam. Briscoe, at the corner of Charles-Street, in Russel-Street, Covent-Garden,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1696.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Text is continuous despite pagination.</note>
                  <note>Identified as Wing B4744 (number cancelled in 2nd ed.) on UMI microfilm set "Early English books, 1641-1700".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of originals in: British Library and Folger Shakespeare Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Money --  England --  History --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-07</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-10</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-10</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:132772-01:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:132772-01:1"/>
            <p>A DISCOURSE OF MONEY.</p>
            <p>Being an ESSAY on that Subject, Hiſtorically and Politically handled.</p>
            <p>WITH <hi>Reflections</hi> on the preſent evil ſtate of the <hi rend="blackletterType">Coin</hi> of this Kingdom; AND <hi>Propoſals</hi> of a Method for the Remedy.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>In a Letter to a Nobleman,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Sam. Briſcoe,</hi> at the Corner of <hi>Charles-Street,</hi> in <hi>Ruſſel-Street, Covent-Garden,</hi> 1696.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:132772-01:2"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:132772-01:2"/>
            <head>THE PUBLISHER TO THE READER.</head>
            <p>THE Author of this Treatiſe, whom I have not the honour to know; whether through Infirmity, or by Ingaging late in the Argu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment; ſeems to ſtand in need of an Apologie with the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick, for not appearing earlier abroad, before the Subject had been ſo far canvas'd. Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore,
<pb facs="tcp:132772-01:3"/>the <hi>Reader</hi> may pleaſe to take Notice, That if he has not preſent leiſure (amidſt the warmth of Debates now on foot upon this Theme) to read and weigh the whole Diſcourſe, in the Method wherein it is writ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten, he may turn to <hi>Page 79,</hi> where the <hi>Dialogue</hi> begins; which diſcourſes and applies the whole Argument to the im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mediate great Queſtion; name<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, <hi>The Cauſes and Reme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies of the Diſeaſe of our Coin.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:132772-01:3"/>
            <head>A DISCOURSE OF Money, &amp;c.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>My Lord,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>YOU command me to give you my judgment on this difficult Subject of <hi>Money,</hi> without Reflecting I fear, that as the Task is too great for my Forces, ſo the
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:132772-01:4"/>time you have alotted me is too little for the work, tho my capacity and talents were never ſo promiſing.</p>
            <p>I am under a further diffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culty by coming thus late into the Diſpute, when others (who beſides their being better able, and having better means to acquit themſelves) have exhau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſted the Argument; ſo that the moſt I ſhall be able to do will be but a Gleaning after their Harveſt.</p>
            <p>Under theſe diſadvantages then of being conſtrain'd to take another method than I wou'd chuſe were I left to my liberty; of avoiding to ſpeak to
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:132772-01:4"/>many <hi>Points,</hi> as having been very pertinently ſpoken to already, and of going out of the beaten Road to find out ſomething that may be thought new, en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tertaining, or inſtructing: If, I ſay, under theſe difficulties I ſhall chance to ſucceed in my attempt, and afford your Lordſhip the leaſt addition of Light to the Knowledge you poſſeſs in moſt Subjects, I ſhall be very well pleas'd whatever pains it may coſt me to obey you. Leaving it entirely to your Election, whether a Child of ſo weak a Father may be of ſtrength to be adventur'd abroad and ſee the World or no.</p>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:132772-01:5"/>
            <p>With this ſhort <hi>Preface,</hi> and under the ſhelter of this juſt Apology, I proceed; purpoſing to obſerve a little more or leſs the following Method.</p>
            <p>I ſhall firſt Diſcourſe gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rally, and go a little into the Hiſtory and Antiquity of Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney.</p>
            <p>Then I ſhall endeavour to ſhew the the Reaſonableneſs and Utility of the Inſtitution and Invention of Money.</p>
            <p>I ſhould have look'd a little into the Hiſtory of the Coin and Mint of <hi>England,</hi> which wou'd have been neceſſary, but I perceive that is already well and painfully perform'd to my
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:132772-01:5"/>hand, by one who is both bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter able, and can have recourſe to better means to do it; and therefore I ſhall therein be ſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent.</p>
            <p>I ſhall Eſſay to ſhew in the expounding my Subject, how and when Money may be Uſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful and Currant, and anſwer all the Ends of that Invention without containing any real or intrinſic Value.</p>
            <p>I ſhall endeavour to explain the meaning of Intrinſic and Extrinſic Value, and ſhew their Uſe, and how it came to paſs that from making Money of worthleſs things, and baſer me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tals, Men came to Coin Gold and Silver; and on that Arti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cle ſhall endeavour to explain
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:132772-01:6"/>and aſſign the Proportion of the Intrinſic Value of Money, and determine the preciſe dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ference there ought to be be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween the Intrinſic and Extrin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſic, or Political Value.</p>
            <p>I ſhall proceed to enquire into the Evils and Maladies in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cident to Money, and the mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtaken Politicks of ſome Nations (eſpecially the <hi>Spaniards</hi>) there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in, to the great Grievance of the People, the Diſhonor, Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage, and Danger of the State.</p>
            <p>I ſhall diſcourſe of Dearneſs and Cheapneſs of Money, and Things; which cannot be un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derſtood without reference to Money, and a compariſon rightly ſtated between them.</p>
            <pb n="7" facs="tcp:132772-01:6"/>
            <p>I ſhall mingle my Specula<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions on this Subject with Hi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtorical and Political Remarks, and frame perhaps, or ſuggeſt Schemes of antient Government, to illuſtrate and explain diffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cult Queſtions, as they may occur about Money.</p>
            <p>I ſhall neceſſarily Treat of <hi>Government, Peace, War, Trade, Arts, Navigation, Exchange, <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſury, Banks,</hi> and <hi>Money</hi> Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as they tend to the Explication and right Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge of my Subject.</p>
            <p>In ſhort, I ſhall travel ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſarily over a great deal of ground, and endeavor to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>move many rubs in my Paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſage before I can fairly come to my Journeys end; which is,
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:132772-01:7"/>to Eſtabliſh a right Notion (at leaſt my conceptions) of Money; and to propoſe a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>medy of the Evil under which the Nation at this day Lan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guiſhes, on the occaſion of the preſent Corruption and la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mentable State of the Coin of this Kingdom.</p>
            <p>I may perhaps go into ſun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dry other particulars which I have not here recited; and it may be thoſe I have may not fall out in the order herein above ſpecified: but I truſt I ſhall no where be underſtood to go induſtriouſly out of my way to meet any foreign or offenſive Matter in the courſe of my Deſign, which is to treat my Subject intelligibly,
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:132772-01:7"/>pertinently, and as becomes an <hi>Engliſh man,</hi> uninfluenc'd by any conſideration that might be thought to byaſs my Love and Veneration to my Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>try.</p>
            <p>The Uſe of Money is of very great Antiquity, as antient as Hiſtory at leaſt; whence may be gather'd, that mankind had very early Notions of the bleſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing of Society, and therein of improving their common eaſe and intercourſe, by invent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and ſubſiſtuting ſomething that ſhou'd render their Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merce one with another more practicable and beneficial, than by Barter or Exchange of one Commodity for another: Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haps
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:132772-01:8"/>too it was conſiſtent e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nough with the Virtue and Simplicity of the firſt Ages of the World, to Coin their Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney of Iron, Braſs, or other inferiour matter or metals, which had very little, or no Intrinſic Value, but was made Currant, and receiv'd an Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trinſic or Political Value from the Stamp and Authority of the Prince or State, within whoſe Territory it paſs'd and was receiv'd, but cou'd be of no uſe without the Bounds of that Power by Virtue where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of it reciv'd that currant Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue; becauſe the profit accru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing by the coinage of baſe Metals being taken and aſſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med by the Prince, it became
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:132772-01:8"/>a Prerogative and Mark of Sovereignty; and as all Fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reign Coin was therefore for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bidden to be receiv'd, ſo it became Penal by that means to the Subject to imitate or falſifie it, as being from thence, I ſuppoſe, juſtly call'd the <hi>Kings Coin.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>But as the Ambition of Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, Luxury and Avarice grew in the World, the love of Money, and the deſire to ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cumulate Wealth to compaſs the means and gratifie the ends of our deprav'd Appetites in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creas'd. But becauſe Ambition, which aims at Extent of Power and Dominion, cou'd not be further'd but by Foreign helps
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:132772-01:9"/>of Power and Means, by Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies and Proviſions of War; becauſe Luxury and a volup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuous Life grew too great to be aſſwag'd by the Native Growth or Product of our re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Climes and Countries; becauſe the Avaricious Man, whoſe Vice is merely to hoard and heap up Riches, perceiv'd that Money in thoſe early days had little or no Intrin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſic Worth, having but a no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minal and arbitrary Signifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation; it being in the power of the Prince or State to alter its value: He therefore cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted by all poſſble means to poſſeſs ſomething elſe not ſo liable to loſs by accident, e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mergencies of State, or caprice
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:132772-01:9"/>of Princes; ſuch as ſhou'd con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain a ſolid unalterable, inde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pendant Univerſal Approba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. Which, in ſhort, is what we mean by Intrinſic Value.</p>
            <p>From theſe Cauſes then, and to anſwer the Ends aforeſaid, we may fairly conclude, that thoſe two noble and univer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſally eſteem'd Metals of Gold and Silver obtain'd to be Coi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned and Manufactur'd into Money; which from thence is properly call'd <hi>Treaſure.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>From the uſe then of Braſs, Iron, or other baſe Coin (which having little or no real Value, and therefore had no Virtue beyond the Extent of that Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:132772-01:10"/>which made it paſs.) Men came from a Domeſtick (as I may ſay) to meditate on an Univerſal Coin; where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by their Intercourſe might be ſpread beyond their own Fron<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiers; ſuch as might obviate all the difficulties of Traffic in the World abroad; as namely, when by their native Fruits or Manufacturies by way of Barter, whether for Luxury or Neceſſity they cou'd not eaſily be ſupply'd, they might have preſent recourſe to, to remove that difficulty, and facilitate their Intercourſe; be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe with Money we may pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſe every thing, but every thing, and very often many things; do in ſome conjun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctures
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:132772-01:10"/>chance not to be Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys-worth. Thus did Money by being made of Gold and Silver, and from no other cauſe, obtain'd that Virtue, and ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quir'd the Reverence that it has in the World.</p>
            <p>If Intrinſic Value then ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pears ſo neceſſary, and that the more any thing contains of that Virtue which intitles it to the general Eſteem, the greater right it will have to our Ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neration; it is a plain conſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quence, that the purer and perfecter the Coin of a King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom is, the more acceptable and popular it will be; for as the plenty and ſcarcity of good Blood in our Natural Bodies,
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:132772-01:11"/>which by infinite and almoſt inperceptible Channels is con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vey'd and diſtributed to the remoteſt Members, eſtabliſhes a good or bad Conſtitution: Such is the Treaſure of the Body Politic, the ſtrength and weakneſs, health and infirmity, whereof (to purſue the Parallel no further) is founded on the plenty or ſcarcity, perfection or impurity of the Coin. Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I will take for granted, that I ſhall not be cenſur'd for ſpinning my Speculation too fine, if I briefly enumerate as they occur to me the Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefits accrewing to the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monwealth, by a wiſe and ſcrupulous care in the Regu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation of our Mint, whereby
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:132772-01:11"/>a juſt, rich, unadulterate Coin may be eſtabliſh'd and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerv'd.</p>
            <p>Firſt, I obſerve that Arts will flouriſh with greater Lu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtre and Perfection; and Indu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtry, the Child of Art and Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther of Riches and Plenty, will by this means be purſued and cultivated; in as much as La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour, which is the Original of Property, will grow more in Uſe and Faſhion, in proporti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on to the value of the Reward. People at this Day do not Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter for Beads and Shells, but will expect a Penyworth for their Peny; and as it is a mark of Slavery, ſo is it the means of Poverty in a State, where
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:132772-01:12"/>the Magiſtrate aſſumes a Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er to ſet what Price he pleaſes on the Publick Coin: It is a ſign of Slavery, becauſe the Subject in ſuch Caſe lives mere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly at the Mercy of the Prince, is Rich, or Poor, has a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petency, or is a Beggar, is a Free-man, or in Fetters at his Pleaſure; for a Man may en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joy enough to Day, and more than will ſuffice to pay his Debts, and to Morrow a De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cree of the Prince, or a Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clamation of the State, to ſerve perhaps ſome ſorry pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Publick End, may declare him a <hi>Bankrupt.</hi> 'Tis a cauſe of Poverty, becauſe Arts and Induſtry by this means loſe their Appetite, ſicken into
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:132772-01:12"/>Sloth, and ſink by degrees in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to Miſery; for where People labour for uncertain or little Gain, the Edge of growing Rich is taken off, Poverty grows into a Habit, and eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry laudable Profeſſion falls in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to Contempt; as it is at this Day in <hi>Spain,</hi> which we behold fallen from a flouriſhing State into the moſt abject forlorn Condition, that it is poſſible for a free unconquer'd King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom to ſink to; much of whoſe Miſery being, I am per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuaded, owing to their want of a due Penetration into mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters of Money, wherein no People play more at faſt and looſe. I ſay, all laudable Arts grow in proportion to the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward;
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:132772-01:13"/>but Gold and Silver, which have obtain'd a real univerſal value, is a ſolid un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>changeable unarbitrary Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compence: Wherefore the ſiner and purer your Money is, the more it will charm and incite to the uſe of thoſe Means that conduct Men to the Poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſion of it.</p>
            <p>The Species of Gold and Silver will by this means be propagated, and increaſe in proportion to the Induſtry and Application of the People to obtain it; becauſe the Species growing more in demand, the uſe of it will ſpread wider; and the more any thing is in requeſt, the ſurer we are of its
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:132772-01:13"/>increaſe, by Peoples ingaging in a more general and ardent En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavour to poſſeſs it.</p>
            <p>The plenty of Gold and Silver which grows from a pure and rich Coin, will raiſe the Value of your Land, which is the Natural Wealth of the State, as Treaſure is the Artifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cial; for, as low Intereſt ſprings from the plenty of Money, ſo Land, which is the ſolid Foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dation of that Security, which inſures the Property of it to the Lender, and which can never increaſe or diminiſh in Quan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tity, muſt indiſputably riſe and fall in Value according to the plenty or ſcarcity of your Treaſure, which will be ever
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:132772-01:14"/>liable to Ebbs and Floods, while States are obnoxious to Revolutions, by Sedition, War, Famine, Peſtilence, or the like.</p>
            <p>The raiſing the Value of your Land, tends to the Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>provement of Husbandry and Tillage; for People, otherwiſe never ſo heavy, have a quick Senſe of the Profit of their Labour, and will beſtow their Coſt and Pains in proportion to the Worth of the Subject-Matter and the Benefit they gather from their Induſtry: This will multiply Husband<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, and propagate a hardy and uſeful Race of People, the leaſt Lucrative, the moſt
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:132772-01:14"/>Innocent and Proſitable of all others to the State whether for peace or war.</p>
            <p>The love of Riches and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire of Gain thus growing up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on us, becomes a greater in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>citement to ingage in all ſorts of Difficulties, to deſpiſe Perils and decline no means what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever that are likely to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duct us to our profit.</p>
            <p>Hence Navigation the Nur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſery of our native Strength, the Rock of our Safety, the Source and Foundation of all our Wealth, Power and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſperity, becomes cheriſh'd and improv'd, and all the incident Arts of that noble and uſeful
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:132772-01:15"/>Profeſſion cultivated and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rich<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>d; and how many hands are Imployed; how many Trades and Profeſſions ſubſiſt and increaſe by the the Art of Shipwrightry alone, excluſive of the Profits flowing to us by our Navigations, is too well known to need my Obſerva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion here.</p>
            <p>Let it be further remark'd, that where your Money is pure, your Coin beautiful and per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect, People will be won to value it in Proportion; and when Intereſt is low, which is ever a ſign of Riches, when it chances to fall of it ſelf, as it will be a means whenever it ſhall be made ſo by a Law.
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:132772-01:15"/>When good Security is hard to find, when Men (of which ſort there are many) have ſcru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples about Uſury, and ſome there are alſo who want Aſſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance to adventure great Sums of Money out of their hands: When theſe and the like Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tives, I ſay, ſhall happen where the Coin of a Kingdom is Pure and without Blemiſh, People will be incourag'd and invit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to hoard and coffer up their Treaſure, in proportion to their Plenty, as there is no doubt Men do their fair Money at this day, on the occaſion of the preſent lamentable Cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruption of our Coin. Which Money ſo reſerv'd and lay'd up, ſhall give no Impediment
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:132772-01:16"/>to Trade and the general Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merce of the Nation; becauſe it will be no other than as it were the over-flowings of our Wealth: And whenever it ſhou'd chance that ſcarcity of Money might be juſtly aſcribed to ſuch or the like cauſe, the Mint when it is ſet on a right Baſis (as ſhall be ſhown by and by) will be ever at hand to ſupply that want. Nor is it likely any ſuch Sums ſo Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſur'd up, can lie longer hid than during the Lives of the Poſſeſſors, which, at their death at fartheſt, becomes ſpread and diſtributed amongſt their Heirs, and takes its courſe again in the Common Currant-Channel of Buſineſs.</p>
            <pb n="27" facs="tcp:132772-01:16"/>
            <p>By thus laying up and hoard<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a proportion of our ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perfluous Wealth, how eager<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſoever over anxious Miſers, and Men of Worldly Minds may contend to the contrary, may, I am perſwaded, without a Paradox, be made intelligible enough to be a means of in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſing the capital Stock of National Treaſure, tho it lie uſeleſs and yields only the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent pleaſure of Poſſeſſion to the injoyer. And how lauda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble it wou'd be, and of what mighty Conſequence it might prove to the Glory, Power, and Felicity of a Nation, (and eſpecially ours) to have the Maſtery of an immenſe Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure ſpread and diſtributed
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:132772-01:17"/>among Myriads of well-minded Subjects, who having it in their power, it will be odds but it will be always in their Will too in any emergency of Danger or Diſtreſs of the State (which is the bottom wherein all their Treaſure is imbark'd) to part with each Man his proportion to the Prince, thereby inable<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing him to ſave the whole. I ask then whether this wou'd not be more eligible to a Think<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Man and an <hi>Engliſhman,</hi> to be always in a capacity of obligeing and gratifying a good Prince, by the moſt ſignal and ſubſtantial Expreſſions that may be of his Duty and good Will: which is parting with his Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney to ſerve and ſupport him;
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:132772-01:17"/>whereby a perpetual concord betwixt Prince and People is preſerv'd, good Laws obtain'd, and ev'ry Grievance cur'd or prevented. Than on the other hand, for a Nation to be un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bleſs'd with a covetous ambi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tious Ruler, who is himſelf a hoarder up of Treaſure, and who by great Parcimony, and perhaps for dangerous Ends ſhall be able out of his ſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Revenue, in a few years, to ingroſs and become Maſter of all the Money in the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, where it muſt lie as dead and uſeleſs as in the moſt con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceal'd Coffers of the People, or be converted to other uſes than thoſe for which it will be given, when regularly de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:132772-01:18"/>and appropriated. We behold the ſuperfluities of moſt Men's Eſtates to run out into Jewels, Plate, and rich Movea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles; all which in time looſe of their Value, and become for the moſt part of damage to the owner. Now if to gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tifie their Vanity, and for bare Oſtentation, Men will yield to this Expence: How much more Praiſe-worthy wou'd it be, and turn better to Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick and Private Account, for every wealthy Man, by cure<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing his mind of the anxious Thoughtfulneſs of letting Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney lie dead by them, as they call it, to have always a pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion of their Store ſo lay'd up in good Money, which as
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:132772-01:18"/>it may be lodg'd with more ſafety, ſo is it kept with better Fruit; for as the making coſts him nothing, ſo the owner loſes nothing by the Faſhion whenſoever he parts with it, as in his Plate, and moſt other things of Value he doth; al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt every thing beſides be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comes the worſe for the wear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, but pure and perfect Coin, which contains its due Intrinſic Value, ſhall, in all likelyhood, be like rich Wine, which ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quires Virtue by its Age; for I think it may be prov'd to a Domonſtration, that Gold and Silver is not likely to grow much more plentiful in the world, but in all probability to riſe in value according to
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:132772-01:19"/>the growing ſcarcity of the Species; which I ſhall endea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour further to explain anon. Furthermore, whatſoever Men have lying by them which they keep not for profit, or ſhew, or preſent uſe, they part with more eaſily, and miſs with leſs pain when it is out of their Poſſeſſion: Nor is it beyond the proſpect of any Thinking Man that ſuch a practiſe of laying up Money in proportion to our Store, may become a means of propagating the Spe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies of Gold and Silver among us, and ſo of lowering the Rates of Uſury; which wou'd beget a retrenching of the worſt and moſt pernicious ſort of Gain of all others in a State,
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:132772-01:19"/>and a borrowing, as I may ſay, from lazy Avarice, to lend on eaſier terms to the induſtrious and painful Merchant, Trades<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man and Artificer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> whoſe prime material being Money, when that ſhall be obtain'd with leſs difficulty, they will be enabled to proſecute their uſeful Callings with more Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fort to themſelves, and greater Fruit to the Commonwealth; for let intereſſed and avarici<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous Men ſay what they can to the contrary, when all is done, the Merchant (and conſequent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly every Trade and Myſtery depending on our Commerce with the World abroad) muſt now adays reſt contented to Trade and Labour for leſs Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:132772-01:20"/>than heretofore, for Reaſons too long to explain here; from which Conſideration, if the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt of Money, either by a Law, or ſome other means, does not fall proportionably, our Rivals abroad, who perhaps ſee better in that <hi>medium,</hi> or ſtand in a better Light than we do, may come to convince us of our Error when too late. I ſay, unleſs wiſe and magiſterial Remedies be apply'd, Trade muſt inevitably decay, languiſh, and give up the Ghoſt, and at length the majority of Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kind be reduc'd to row in the Uſurers Gallies: But this whole Paragraph may perhaps ſeem ſuperfluous, or be thought too long a digreſſion; wherefore
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:132772-01:20"/>in one word, if ſober and well<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>principl'd Men would weigh and digeſt this Propoſition, I am in little doubt but they would ſee Truth or Probabili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty enough in it to win their Approbation, for as it promi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeth thoſe good Effects and more than I have enumerated, ſo like <hi>Goliah</hi>'s Sword, which, tho' it ſeem to lie by the Walls, it may in time come to be ſaid there is nothing like it; for it may chance to tend towards the cure of that Leproſie whoſe Contagion is become epidemi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cal; infecting our beſt and nobleſt Families, whoſe An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſtors thought Uſury as infa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mous as Forgery, which, in an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cient and more innocent Times,
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:132772-01:21"/>ſtood branded by the Laity, and cenſur'd by the Church. For Uſury is no other than a kind of a petty Tyranny, where the Borrower ſells him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf into Bondage to the Len<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, who are for the moſt part the crueleſt Task-Maſters in the World: And becauſe Uſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry was a Burden upon the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jority, for the ſake of a few, and yielded no increaſe to the Publick Stock, it was therefore forbidden to the <hi>Jews</hi> by the all-wiſe Law-giver, God him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf; that is to ſay, among themſelves, while to their Neighbors round about (whom they had leave to vex and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poveriſh) it was permitted them to lend and let out their
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:132772-01:21"/>Money on the hardeſt terms, the Avarice of that ſordid Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion could ſuggeſt. In a word, that I may not be thought to declaim while I am ſo much in Earneſt, let me once for all obſerve to you, That where a Government is eaſie, where Arts and Induſtry flouriſh, where Money abounds, and Trade is incourag'd, where In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt is low, and where all thoſe Benefits accrue to a Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, which we have ſpecified and endeavour'd to prove, to be in a great degree the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duct of an excellent and well-underſtood Coin: That State, I ſay, under ſuch an Oecono<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my, ſhall above all, and to crown their Felicity, increaſe
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:132772-01:22"/>and abound proportionably in People; ſuch a Country, like a great Market, where every good and needful thing is to be had, ſhall invite every Body to come; and People will a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bide and ſet up their Reſt there where they can be moſt at their Eaſe. This, as it will further inſure our Happineſs by augmenting our Strength; ſo, according to Sir <hi>William Petty</hi>'s reckoning (who was a moſt excellent Calculator) our Treaſure will grow from our Numbers, which is from the Power it ſelf that Protects our Poſſeſſion of it, by the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion of Ten Pounds <hi>per</hi> Head <hi>per Annum</hi> for every Man the Nation contains; after
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:132772-01:22"/>which Rule of computing, One hundred thouſand additional Inhabitants only, will amount to a Million of Pounds profit <hi>per Annum</hi> to the Publick; and ſuch an acceſſion of Wealth and Power to a Land of Plen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty as ours is, that perhaps yields, or may be made to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duce Suſtenance for double the Inhabitants that now live on it, ought to be in every ones Wiſh and Aim to com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſs.</p>
            <p>From my general Notions of Coin, the Original, Inſtitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, Nature and Uſe of Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, which ſeemed a neceſſary Induction towards the due Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plication of my Subject, I pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:132772-01:23"/>to obſerve, That Mankind had no ſooner found it neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſary, from the Reaſons we have rendred, that their Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney ſhould contain Intrin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſic Value, when their choice of the Matter whereof to make it, fell inevitably on Gold and Silver; from the general E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſteem, the Durableneſs, the Beauty, Ductileneſs and Puri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of thoſe Metals, whereby they became every where more valued among civiliz'd Nati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons than any other Species; that is to ſay, a leſs quantity thereof would be barter'd or exchang'd for a greater of any other Matter or Metal what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever. Now that which con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tains more value in leſs com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſs,
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:132772-01:23"/>is neceſſarily more worth, will lie in leſs room, is tran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſported with more eaſe, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceal'd and ſecur'd from Vio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lence with leſs trouble, and the Poſſeſſor enjoys it with leſs Hazard and Anxiety.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Tacitus</hi> obſerves, that the <hi>Scythians</hi> (otherwiſe barba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous enough) abounded with Gold: The Reaſon was plain, they were a Nation always in motion, flying, marching and wandring with great Celerity; had no abiding Place, and therefore naturally and wiſely choſe to be Maſters of ſuch a Species of Wealth as they cou'd move, tranſport, ſtow, and diſpoſe of moſt commodiouſly.
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:132772-01:24"/>From hence then we may con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clude, the World came to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termine their choice of Gold and Silver, whereof to make their Money, which for the ſake of, and in order to that extent of Commerce, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of they began to have a taſte, this kind of Money being de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign'd for perpetual Motion, was more apt for Circulation, and better adjuſted to the Uſes of Intercourſe, than any other whatſoever.</p>
            <p>From the Reaſonableneſs, or Neceſſity, or both, of the choice Men made of Gold and Silver, whereof to make and coin their Money, it may not be much out of our way to
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:132772-01:24"/>make a ſhort Inquiry into the Original of the Rates and Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue of Money, how it became determin'd how it riſes and falls, why and how the Propor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion between Money and Things varies, and by what Rules, to attain a right and uſeful No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of this intricate Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject.</p>
            <p>Mankind for the Offence of our firſt Parents was by his Maker Sentenc'd to Labour; <hi>By thy ſweat ſhalt thou live,</hi> ſays the Text; that is, thou ſhalt Labour or Die. This Sentence as it was the fruit of Original Sin, ſo it ſeems to be the Foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dation of Original Property: We can have no title to any
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:132772-01:25"/>thing; we can call nothing ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſtly our own; we can nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther be ſuſtain'd, cloath'd, or preſerve our Being, but by La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour: The Earth, our Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Mother by which we are nouriſh'd, will yield us nothing without Labour and Cultiva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. I go to a River or a Fountain to fetch water for my uſe, the water was nobo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy's, had no Proprietor, and was no more worth than the Labour which I beſtow'd in fetching it; from whence a natural Right and Property of that water is deriv'd to me, and I may diſpoſe of it to another for ſo much of ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing elſe which he hath and I want, as my labour may be
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:132772-01:25"/>deem'd worth. You have Gold and Silver, and I have none; you wou'd imploy me for a year in your Service; I am a poor Man who live by my Day-Labour and have but from hand to mouth, as they ſay. Now 'tis plain, if you com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pute what Sum of Money will ſuffice to pay for the Labour that produces all thoſe Species of things that muſt go to ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtain Cloth, and keep me for this term of a Year, that Sum is what I ought to receive for my Wages; and that term being reduc'd to days, will ſhew what I ought to have <hi>per diem</hi> for my Service, which in natural Juſtice is enough. By this In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance of a Contract, we may
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:132772-01:26"/>be enlight'ned in the Notion, Uſe, and Value of Property, which by no other way can be ſo eaſily rated; and by this Rule and no other, we calcu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>late and make our Eſtimates of the value of Works and Things; namely, by beginning our reckoning from ſimple and uncompounded Labour; which, I ſay, is the Original of Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prety, is every Freeman's own, who has a right to ſell it for what it is worth; and how that is calculated I have en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deavour'd to explain.</p>
            <p>The next thing to be ſought in this Enquiry, is the Value cumparatively of Gold and Sil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver, with other things which
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:132772-01:26"/>are bought with Money, name<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, how it comes to paſs that juſt ſo much Money, or ſuch a quantity of Gold or Silver, a little more or leſs, comes to be a competent Price for ſuch Things or Commodities as we need, and which to ſupply our Neceſſities we are oblig'd to goe to Market for and Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſe with Money.</p>
            <p>This <hi>Query</hi> is in like man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner beſt reſolv'd by an Exam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, which may ſhew us in one view, how the Value of Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney comes to be regulated to ſuch a Proportion with other Species, ſo as to be conſiſtent with the Ends and Uſes of Traffick and Intercourſe, to
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:132772-01:27"/>which Purpoſe it was Origi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nally inſtituted.</p>
            <p>It is not hard to ſuppoſe, that a Thouſand Men with their Wives and Families ſhould tranſport themſelves by agree<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, to ſome Spot or Iſland, as Hiſtory tells us the <hi>Veneti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans</hi> did, and others have done; invited by the Fertility and Bounty of the Soil and Cli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mate, which might be made to yield every thing needful for the ſupply of their Neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſities. We may farther eaſily imagine, that a due Proporti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of People of all uſeful Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſions, were forted and cho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſen by joynt Conſent, whereof to form and compoſe this lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:132772-01:27"/>Body of a Republick; eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry one, as it chanc'd carrying with him what Treaſure he had; which Treaſure, in order to their Eſtabliſhment, is caſt into a Common Bank, and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtin'd to the Uſe of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munity. This Colony we can grant plants its ſelf where they have no Intercourſe or Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munication with the reſt of Mankind, but muſt live on their own Stock, and he ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtain'd and ſupply'd by their Labour and the Fruit of their own Induſtry. Now 'tis plain, That with reaſonable Men, the firſt thing they would go about would be to deliberate how, by Laws and Inſtitutions, to eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſh themſelves ſo as to live
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:132772-01:28"/>at their beſt Eaſe. They know the Uſe of Money, whereof they have a certain Stock in Bank, which being never like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly to increaſe, nor, as it may be manag'd, is it abſolutely neceſſary to their Happineſs that it ſhould; wherefore they deviſe how to make this Stock of Treaſure, be it more or leſs, to become a certain Fund for Perpetuity, whereon to eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſh their common Inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſe; in order to which, what is more obvious than firſt to reckon and determine how many Species of Things, and no more, are or ſhall be neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſary to be had or us'd for their ſimple and commodious Subſiſtence. Next they will
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:132772-01:28"/>calculate what Quantity will be neceſſary of each reſpective Kind. And Thirdly, They will find the comparative va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue of theſe Species one with another, which is known by the labour each Thing will coſt to make and it fit for their Uſe: For I obſerve, that every Man's Day-labour muſt produce his daily Subſiſtence, or the Community at a long run muſt diſſolve: This being known and eſtabliſh'd, the next Step, which is very eaſie to make, is to calculate from the reſpective Ages of the People, whereof our little Body-Poli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tick is compos'd, a mean pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portional Expence of the above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid Species <hi>per Annum,</hi> neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſary
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:132772-01:29"/>to one ſingle Member thereof; that is, how much La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour it will coſt to produce all thoſe <hi>Particulars</hi> that any one ſingle Perſon ſhall need or be permitted to conſume or ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pend within the circuit of one Year; to which Revolution I the rather limit it, becauſe within that ſpace the Earth yields her Increaſe, and the or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinary Changes of Things hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen, and it being the great Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riod by which Time it ſelf is meaſur'd: This being obtain'd, and your Stock of Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure known, will produce a Rule that will amount to a De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monſtration for aſſigning a Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue to your Money. Admit then for Evidence-ſake, that
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:132772-01:29"/>your Number conſiſts of Ten thouſand Souls, this Ten thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand People will by your Cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culation conſume a known and certain Quantity of the above<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid ſeveral Species, which will coſt ſuch a Proportion of Man's Labour to produce; now up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on examination into your Treaſure, we will ſuppoſe you find juſt Two hundred thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Pounds in Bank; divide your Two hundred thouſand Pounds Caſh by Ten thouſand, which was the Number of your People at that time, and the Quotient will be Twenty, which is twenty Pounds in Money; which twenty Pounds muſt in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>evitably anſwer for and be equivalent to the Labour of
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:132772-01:30"/>any one, <hi>caeteris paribus per An.</hi> then upon reducing your Year into Days, the Product will be about Ten Pence <hi>per Diem,</hi> and ſo much was the Day-labour of one Man worth at that time; that is, while your People and your Treaſure hold this Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion one with another; wherefore by this Rule every Member of this Community has a right to receive Twenty Pounds out of the common Stock, to be inabled to bring the Year about: Which will beget a conſtant intelligible Circulation of your Coin, by you intended to anſwer all the Ends of Traffick and Inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſe within the circuit of the Year.</p>
            <pb n="55" facs="tcp:132772-01:30"/>
            <p>But your People you will ſay, in ſo healthful a Soil and Climate, where neither the Sword, Plague, or Famine is likely to diminiſh them, will ſoon by the courſe of Nature multiply, but your Treaſure cannot; and in ſuch Caſe how will your Money, which was but juſt enough before, ſuffice then? The Anſwer to this Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jection is eaſie, and will ſhew us at once the chief Cauſes of the riſing and falling of Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, that is the Dearth or Plen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of the Species of Things which happens in the wide World; where Government comes to be relax'd and Chance for the moſt part Rules, where Neceſſity, which is blind, ſtum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles
<pb n="56" facs="tcp:132772-01:31"/>on Remedies and Expedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ents next at hand to redreſs the Evils of our Miſmanage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment or want of Foreſight: But by our Hypotheſis there can never happen any ſuch thing as dear and cheap, plen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and ſcarcity of Money; which I thus prove. I ſay that your Treaſure, which is Two hundred thouſand Pounds, and which is not to increaſe or di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſh, is by this Contrivance and Calculation plainly ren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred a ſufficient Fund to anſwer all the Ends of Intercourſe in this little Republick of Ten thouſand People, but your ſtock of Money being impoſſible to increaſe, and very probable that our Numbers of People
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:132772-01:31"/>ſhould; what Expedient can be found to get over this Obje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction ſince by our Calculation the Money you have in Bank is but juſt enough for the Uſes of your preſent Numbers. Thus, I ſay, this ſeeming Difficulty is obviated; after the Revoluti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of one Year you make a <hi>Cenſus,</hi> and upon the Roll you find your People increas'd one in Ten: Hereupon by the ſame Calculation and Rule of Proportion, you plainly find that Nine Pence this Year in Money muſt inevitably be worth, purchaſe and buy in the Market, whatſoever the laſt Year coſt ten Pence; and ſo, if your Numbers come to dou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, that which originally coſt
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:132772-01:32"/>a Shilling, muſt then coſt but Six Pence: The like Rule ſerves in Caſe of the dimunition of your People, by which means your Money ſhall, by exact Methods of Proportion, be preſerv'd in a due and perpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tual Balance with the Species it is to purchaſe; and the Price of Labour by the ſame Rule regulated and duly ſtated, and your Stock of Treaſure, by this means, becomes an everlaſting unexhauſtible Fund, to anſwer all the Uſes of the Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment. And there is no doubt but by this manner of Calcu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation, or ſome way like it, the Law of <hi>Aſſize</hi> was found and eſtabliſh'd, whereby every need<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful thing was yearly rated and
<pb n="59" facs="tcp:132772-01:32"/>ſet at a certain Price, which in frugal States is ſtill practis'd, and it were to be wiſh'd it were every where more in Faſhion.</p>
            <p>I am well aware that Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jectors, Mony-mongers, Bank-Brokers, and petty Dealers in Politicks, will be apt to take this Argument by the wrong Handle, and be very earneſt and in pain to ſhew me a thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Errors in my Hypothe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſis; but theſe Gentlemen may pleaſe to underſtand, that as I am not conſcious of any Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lents in the Politicks, ſo nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther is it my Purpoſe to wade in ſo deep Water, a depth I know ſo much above my head;
<pb n="60" facs="tcp:132772-01:33"/>let it ſuffice, that by this Scheme of a little State, where Religi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, Juſtice, Innocence, Tempe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance, and Induſtry are the Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſis, the Building may ſtand, and Rules may be calculated to a Demonſtration for its Perpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuity. And the farther Men wander by Ambition, Violence, Luxury, Avarice, Sloth, and the like Irregularities, from the Innocence and Simplicity of this Original, the harder it is to conceive and propound Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>medies for the Evils ſuch Er<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rors produce. Wherefore, as we know an Unite to be the beginning and ſimpleſt of Numbers, yet find too, that it is the Baſis of the Pyramid on which <hi>Arithmetick</hi> it ſelf ſtands
<pb n="61" facs="tcp:132772-01:33"/>and is ſuſtain'd; ſo upon the ſimpleſt and leaſt compound<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Government, the Unite, as I may ſay, of a State, unmix'd and clean from all Infection of the Corruptions of humane Frailty; we can beſt build our Speculations when we have a mind to amuſe our ſelves on the Subject of Laws and Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, becauſe 'tis to that Fountain alone which we can ſafely reſort for Succours in the greateſt ſtreights of our Medi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation, deriving ſo much Light from the Reaſon and Evidence contain'd in a ſimple, ſound, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gular Form of State, which is governable and durable to a Demonſtration; I ſay, we may be beſt aided in our Notions
<pb n="62" facs="tcp:132772-01:34"/>by reference to this Original, when our Thoughts are buſied about any other Form, how diverſify'd, diſtreſs'd, or diſeas'd ſoever: And for this Reaſon, and no other, have I conceiv'd and produc'd this Pattern, which ſerving my Purpoſe to exemplifie the Facility of ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taining a due underſtanding of my Subject of Money alone, affords no juſt Latitude for Criticks to buſie themſelves a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout any collateral Reflecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons.</p>
            <p>From this principal Rule then being taught to make a general Judgment of Money, its Nature, Uſe and Properties, we may with eaſe be ſupply'd
<pb n="63" facs="tcp:132772-01:34"/>with Reaſons ſorted to every incidence of that Subject; as namely (to mention a few) why Labour heretofore in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land</hi> was worth but a Penny a Day, which now is ten or twenty times that Value? Why an Ox that was then ſold for a Noble, is now worth Ten or Fifteen Pounds. How it came to paſs that ſuch nume<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rous Armies were heretofore pay'd and ſuſtain'd when Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney was ſo hard to find, and the like? ſo that in ſhort, by this clew we may be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ducted through all the Laby<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinths of our dark and intri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cate Subject, and from the right Knowledge of the Cauſes be inabled to take better aim in
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:132772-01:35"/>our Deliberations about the Effects; for as Mankind grew to ſwerve from thoſe firſt few rules which were adjuſted to the ſimplicity of Original Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, the love of Eaſe which is natural, (Labour being a kind of pain, which we wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lingly ſhun) introduc'd Vio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lence; the ſtronger compelling the weaker to Labour, while he liv'd at his Eaſe. Sloth and Idleneſs thus indulg'd, begat a taſte of Pleaſure; Pleaſure fru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctify'd into Luxury and Exceſs. This gave up the Reins to the Empire of the Paſſions, which multiply'd by the Power they gain'd, and became ſo many Tyrants and Task-Maſters; which at this day Rule with ſo
<pb n="65" facs="tcp:132772-01:35"/>much Cruelty over Mankind, and is the Sourſe of all thoſe Vices, Impieties, and Miſrule which at this Day infect the World: And how various and diverſify'd, how jarring and diſcordant ſoever they may be amongſt themſelves, do never<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>theleſs all combine and unite in the ſingle Service of this one Idol Money, whoſe <hi>Myſteries,</hi> in ſuch a <hi>Babel</hi> of worſhip, we are not to wonder ſhould be ſo hard to unfold.</p>
            <p>By theſe Incroachments then upon the Liberties of right Reaſon, through the growth and corruption of our Appe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tites, which begat ſo many de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viations from the firſt Standard
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:132772-01:36"/>ſimple Maxims of Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, here by me, for Illuſtra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion ſake, propounded; we may by Analogy and Compariſon be furniſh'd with Helps in our Judgment on every Doubt a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout this intangled Subject: As the <hi>Jews</hi> heretofore had re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>courſe to the Sanctuary, where all their Original Standards of Coins, Weights and Meaſures were lodg'd, and from that Reaſon I ſuppoſe they were call'd the <hi>Shekel,</hi> the <hi>Balance,</hi> and the <hi>Cubit of the Sanctuary.</hi> Purſuant then to our Method, let us inquire what can be thought to diſturb the Tran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quility of our little Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wealth: To which I anſwer, That nothing (humanly ſpeak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing)
<pb n="67" facs="tcp:132772-01:36"/>but a departing from, or a relaxation of that Strictneſs of Order and Diſcipline on which their Proſperity was founded: And this may ſpring from infinite Cauſes, but I will inſtance only one or two; and firſt, by Ambition from with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out or within, by invading of their Neighbours, or by their invading them: This ariſes from Injuſtice, which infers Hoſtility, and Hoſtility intro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duces Violence of every kind, whereby the Balance becomes broken, and the Harmony of our little State threatned with Diſſolution. But, to go no further than one ſingle abſtra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted inſtance of this Vice of Ambition, let us ſuppoſe a
<pb n="68" facs="tcp:132772-01:37"/>tenth part of the Number which compoſes our Colony to be deſtin'd to the War: Is it not evident, that if one Man out of ten ſhall be taken from the Plough, or any other civil Occupation, and diverted to other Uſes, foreign to the O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riginal Eſtabliſhment, who ſhall be thereby exempted from the Labour and Duties incident to his Memberſhip of a peace<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able State, that the remaining Nine muſt by their Labour produce the Subſiſtance of Ten? This I think is plain, and from hence, as the diſpropor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion increaſes, Scarcity, Pover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, and Neceſſity are intro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duc'd; for the Labour of the Induſtrious becomes at length
<pb n="69" facs="tcp:132772-01:37"/>too little to ſuſtain and pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vide for thoſe who live ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cus'd from Labour, and who muſt ſubſiſt whether they con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tribute towards their Subſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtence or no: Whereupon De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpair, Deſertion, Depopulation, and every evil Incident to War enſues. Hence then, I ſay, doth Ambition (which is a Drop<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſie of the Mind, the thirſt whereof is increas'd by the poſſeſſion of what it moſt co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vets to aſſwage it) makes a Breach in our Eſtabliſhment, and urges a recourſe to other Means and Methods than were originally neceſſary to the well-being of the State; and thus Treaſure becomes need<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful, is more ſought after, and
<pb n="70" facs="tcp:132772-01:38"/>conſequently more ſcarcy and more worth: For, as the wiſe Man ſaith, <hi>Money anſwers all things;</hi> ſo is it moſt true, that it becomes the only Plaiſter to all the Sores that are made and feſter through the malignity of this dangerous Diſeaſe, Am<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bition; and tho' civil Neceſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties ſhould clamour never ſo loud, 'tis not heard amidſt the claſhing of Arms and Noiſe of Cannon, for Military Wants preſs to be reliev'd like <hi>Spaniſh</hi> Beggars, with their Hand on their Sword, and plead a ſtron<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger Title to our Compliance than any other Demand, how needful and juſt ſoever: And this indeed is the Root and O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riginal of Mens deſires to ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire
<pb n="71" facs="tcp:132772-01:38"/>Riches; becauſe they would be out of the Power of thoſe Accidents which threaten their Repoſe, and covet to poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſs ſo much thereof as they conceive may ſuffice for them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves and others. But this Fund, whether Publick or Pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vate, has a Bottom, and while the Cauſe continues the Effects grow every Day leſs and leſs ſupportable, and in the upſhot, as I have ſhewn, terminates in Miſery and Deſolation. Thus we behold, how by this ſingle Inſtance of Ambition, which is an Enemy to our Eſtabliſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, the Order and Oecono<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>my of our ſuppos'd Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wealth is broken, and the State runs to ruine; becauſe
<pb n="72" facs="tcp:132772-01:39"/>the Means that are to miniſter to it have Limits, but Ambiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on has none.</p>
            <p>Avarice, which is an irregu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar love of Money, ariſing from a falſe Fear of Want or Poverty, and grows into a ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bit of accumulating Riches, from an over-anxious obſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation of the Streights People are often driven to, by Mens breaking through the Bounda<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ries of good Government, is another Evil, of pernicious con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſequence to the very Eſſence of the Eſtabliſhment we have erected; for, let it be ſuppos'd that Uſury alone, which is the Darling and Firſt-born Evil of this Vice, ſhould chance (by in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dulging this Error) to be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>troduc'd,
<pb n="73" facs="tcp:132772-01:39"/>(without mention of manifold other Miſchiefs which attend it,) and that there were but ten <hi>Jews</hi> or Money-Mongers, with each one hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Pound in his Pocket, ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted into the State, and theſe Miſers had leave to lend their Money at Ten <hi>per Cent. per An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>num</hi> Intereſt; what think you would be the Conſequence of this Violationof our Eſtabliſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment? Why plainly this, That in fifty or threeſcore Years the Uſurers would become Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters of all your Treaſure; that is, your whole Stock of two hundred thouſand Pounds, Original Money, would with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in that ſpace of time center in their Coffers; which is true to a Demonſtration.</p>
            <pb n="74" facs="tcp:132772-01:40"/>
            <p>I might inforce manifold In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtances of the Fruit of Miſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>government, and by recurring as occaſion ſhould be given to our original Form of a little Commonwealth, ſhew by plain Political <hi>Arithmetick,</hi> and evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent Calculation, how and by what proportions Error pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vails, and by what Steps the Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy Politick ſickens and diſſolves; as, namely, through Sedition, Luxury, Prodigality, Sloth, and the like, but theſe may ſuffice for Samples, whereby to ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plain my general Notions of Money, which I thought a ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſary Induction to the Que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtion under debate.</p>
            <p>I come now to draw Uſe from the Doctrines I have de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liver'd:
<pb n="75" facs="tcp:132772-01:40"/>Wherefore to apply them to our preſent Caſe, I ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerve our Government in the preſent Conjuncture, to be un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der two very pinching Diffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culties about Money; the one, from the exorbitant preſent Occaſion for the conſumption of our Treaſure; the other, from our Coins being ſo abo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minably adulterated, dimi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſh'd, and abus'd. As to the <hi>Firſt,</hi> I am not qualify'd to determine what the Nation can ſpare: But, for the <hi>Second,</hi> I am ſure I may ſay, it is more than we can poſſibly preſume to will not therefore preſume to meddle with the Merits, or en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter into the Neceſſity of the one, as not being mine; but
<pb n="76" facs="tcp:132772-01:41"/>the Buſineſs of the Great Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cil, now met, by whoſe Wiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom that important Queſtion ought to be diſcuſs'd; but, in the other Point, I conceive it can give no reaſonable diſtaſt to interpoſe ones Opinion, who by being an unbiaſs'd Obſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver, may, 'tis likely, ſtand in a Light proper enough to diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern; whoſe Tongue being un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty'd by the danger he ſees, may have a little Right to lend a word of Warning to divert an impending Stroak, whereof he is ſure, when ever it lights, to have a ſhare of the Smart: Wherefore let me take leave to ſay, without meaning the leaſt Offence or Injury to any ſingle Man, and for no other
<pb n="77" facs="tcp:132772-01:41"/>End than to ſet a Sea-mark, whereby to ſhun this Rock for the future; that had our Pi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lots look'd well out, this hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vy Diſaſter, under which the Nation grieves, had never be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fallen us; being a Miſchief plainly begotten for want of foreſight of thoſe in Authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, and was propagated to the dangerous degree wherein we now behold it, by the Villainy and guilty Practiſes of <hi>Gold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſmiths, Bankers, Reſiners,</hi> and <hi>Money-Brokers,</hi> &amp;c. who have been Gainers, Incouragers, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceivers, and Pourveyors to this abominable Crime; and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſequently, all Sharers in the guilt of ſo much Blood as the ſeverity of our Laws hath
<pb n="78" facs="tcp:132772-01:42"/>drawn to puniſh it; of the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Sufferings the Nation is under in the Conſequence, and of the Expence of the Remedy, which will be very great when ever we go about it.</p>
            <p>Being now, after a longer Voyage than I intended, ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riv'd within view of my Port, and conſequently oblig'd to ſteer my courſe with more caution than in the wide Sea of Generals was neceſſary, I ſhall therefore I think do beſt right to the ſubject I am treat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, by reſolving the whole matter now reſting to be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bated into Dialogue, and the rather becauſe I ſee abundance of queſtions every where made, and doubts rais'd about it; I
<pb n="79" facs="tcp:132772-01:42"/>ſhall therefore digeſt the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maining and principal part of my Diſcourſe into Queſtion and Anſwer, <hi>viz.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Queſtion, <hi>Why is our Engliſh Coin call'd Sterling?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſwer,</hi> This is doubtful, but the prevailing Opinion is, that Money was firſt Coin'd and made a Native of <hi>England</hi> at a Town of that Name, about the Ninth Century, and was thence call'd <hi>Sterling Money;</hi> before which time perhaps the <hi>Roman</hi> Coin, and that of other civiliz'd Nations, was the Cur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rant Money among us, as <hi>Cob's</hi> and all ſorts of Outlandiſh Coin go at this day, or very lately did in <hi>Ireland.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="80" facs="tcp:132772-01:43"/>
            <p>Q. <hi>Have there been any Alte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rations made in the Mint of</hi> Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land <hi>ſince this firſt Eſtabliſhment; becauſe there is a great deal of talk, and People make much a-do about the Sacredneſs of our Stan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dard; and much talk there is about the Myſteries of the Mint,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> There have been many Changes, Reductions and Eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſhments made in the Mint ſince King <hi>Edward</hi> the Firſt, whatever were before; in whoſe Reign the Proportion of the <hi>Denarius</hi> or Penny, which Originally was the twentieth part of an Ounce, became al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter'd from twenty pence, to twenty ſix, from thence (as ſeeming Reaſon of State per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>haps
<pb n="81" facs="tcp:132772-01:43"/>ſuggeſted) to thirty two, from thirty two to forty Pence, from forty to forty five, and thence to ſixty Pence the Ounce; and this laſt happen'd in the Reign of Queen <hi>Eliza<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beth;</hi> from which time to this day, there has not been I take for granted, the leaſt Reforma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion made in the <hi>Mint</hi> by any ſolemn Publick Act of State.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>I deſire to be inform'd what the Motives might be for ſo ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Alterations as you have enu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merated; for, methinks, wiſe Men ſhould not alter and determine in a Caſe of this Magnitude, without ſome very well-grounded Reaſons.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> I confeſs I am to ſeek for a ſolid Reaſon for their
<pb n="82" facs="tcp:132772-01:44"/>ſo doing, unleſs it were to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pagate the Species, and ſo ſpread it wider among the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, by mincing it into ſo ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny leſſer Parts, to the end eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Body, how poor ſoever; might ſhare in the Pleaſure of poſſeſſing it; go to Market with more eaſe, and manage their common Traffick with leſs difficulty; for, when a Pul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>let was ſold for a Peny, what Species of current Coin could be found to buy a thing that was not worth the twentieth part of a Pullet, I cannot gueſs; for it is plain, we go to the Shops and the Market at this day, to purchaſe ſundry things, for our Money, that are not the twentieth or the fortieth
<pb n="83" facs="tcp:132772-01:44"/>part of the value of a Pullet; and we have no Reaſon to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clude but our Fore-fathers did the ſame: Wherefore I muſt give you this for my beſt Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, till I can be furniſh'd with a better.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>Would there be any good or harm in changing on, by enact<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, for Example, that the Ounce of Standard Silver, that now is eſtabliſh'd at ſixty Pence, ſhould be rated at ſeventy or eighty Pence, and ſo forward, as Reaſon may ſeem to ſuggeſt?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> If you only mean bare<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly the ſubdividing your Ounce of Silver into leſſer Particles, and do not intend by this <hi>Que<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtion</hi> to put a value, of your own making, upon the Ounce
<pb n="84" facs="tcp:132772-01:45"/>of your Standard Silver, (for that will be the Subject of ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther great <hi>Queſtion,</hi>) then I think it would only beget a good deal of Trouble and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tricacy in Buſineſs and Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counts, now that the Nation is grown ſo deeply ingag'd in Fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reign Trade and Commerce: Other good or harm I ſee none in it; for our Coin is now caſt and eſtabliſh'd into ſo low a Denomination, that the pooreſt People have none of thoſe Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pediments in their Dealings, which heretofore might be thought to vex and incumber them, when their Peny was the twentieth part of an Ounce, which is now grown to be the ſixtieth; and when that was
<pb n="85" facs="tcp:132772-01:45"/>the loweſt current Silver Coin, ſaving only that in thoſe days People for their convenience divided that Peny, either by breaking it, or by Sciſſors, di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viding it into four parts; which Species of Money, tho' now almoſt quite worn out and extinct, has yet within our Memory been pretty plenty, and that was our old thin blind Groats, which I believe, and think I have ſome reaſon ſo to do, were for the moſt part thoſe original Pence or <hi>Denarius's,</hi> that were coin'd while the Peny continu'd to be the twentieth part of an Ounce, and obtain'd to be cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led Groats; perhaps from the old <hi>Saxon</hi> or <hi>Daniſh</hi> word <hi>Grott,</hi>
               <pb n="86" facs="tcp:132772-01:46"/>(which is <hi>great,</hi>) that is, the great Peny; to diſtinguiſh it from the latter Peny, which was ſo much leſs.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>How long think you Silver-Money, which is in continual uſe and circulation, may laſt? For, it is plain, it wears and grows ligh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter by motion and uſage, and at length, without clipping or dimi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhing by Art, will wear out of it ſelf, and become too light to paſs.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> My <hi>Anſwer</hi> to the fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>going <hi>Queſtion</hi> may be a ſort of ſolution to this, namely, that if thoſe Groats were the old Peny, it is near Four hundred Years ago ſince that Species was laſt coin'd; but this depends much upon the ſize of your
<pb n="87" facs="tcp:132772-01:46"/>Coin, and the quantity of cur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent Money in Stock and Uſe, and other Circumſtances, of no great moment to mention here.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>I think, however, one good <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſe may be made of this Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervation; and that is, to calcu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>late from thence a little, more or leſs, by what Proportions current Money may waſte, and at length be worn out; for 'tis plain, that by the bare uſage, telling, and mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion in its Circulation, it will diminiſh, and at a long run be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſum'd: Whence we gather, that if there were no other way to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy it, there muſt be a ſupply from abroad to obviate that Evil, how little ſoever it may ſeem: Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I pray give me your Opinion therein.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="88" facs="tcp:132772-01:47"/>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> If that be the uſe you would make of this <hi>Query,</hi> and you but grant me leave to ſtate the <hi>Queſtion</hi> on the Proportion of our Moneys wearing out in the ſpace of four hundred years, then it is viſible that your Stock of Money, without a pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portionable Recruit, will, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out any other cauſe, be total<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly extinct within that ſpace of time; and ſo by Calculation it will be found to waſte after the Rate of a quarter <hi>per Cent. per Annum;</hi> that is, five Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings in the hundred Pounds; but then you muſt ſuppoſe it to be all ſmall Money; as there is reaſon to believe it was in thoſe Days; for I do not know whether Crowns, Half-crowns,
<pb n="89" facs="tcp:132772-01:47"/>Shillings, and Six-pences, are above two hundred Years old, if ſo much; by which Propor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, at leaſt, it is found, I ſay, that your Money muſt be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pair'd to keep the Balance e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven. And by this reckoning too we may gather, that our Money naturally and neceſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rily waſtes one eighth part as much as ſome Nations take for the Intereſt of their Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>Have there not been other kinds of Regulations and Changes made in our</hi> Mint, <hi>beſides thoſe you have mention'd?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> Yes, ſeveral; but let it ſuffice to mention only one in King <hi>Henry</hi> the Eighth's time, which Prince, by his Profuſions
<pb n="90" facs="tcp:132772-01:48"/>in pompous Living, Spectacles, and vain Wars, being driven to great Streights for want of Money, which the Nation could by no means ſupply: That Prince was made to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve that he might be a very great Gainer by embaſing his Coin, namely, (for Example-ſake, for I am not ſure of the Proportion) by the allowing but Nine Peny worth of fine Silver to the Shilling, and ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plying the reſt with Allay, and then telling the People, by his Proclamation, that the new Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, which was intrinſically worth but Nine Pence, ſhould paſs for as much as the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Shilling, which was worth Twelve Pence; by which means
<pb n="91" facs="tcp:132772-01:48"/>he would ſave or gain five and twenty <hi>per Cent,</hi> in the pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of his Debts, and in the pay of his Armies, and the like his Fleets, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Q. <hi>What Objection does there lie againſt ſuch a Project, when the ſtreights of a Prince or State are preſſing?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> There are manifold Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jections, ſo manifeſt, ſo juſt, and of ſo great moment, that it would be tedious to enu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merate them; which that Prince ſoon ſaw, and endea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour'd to reform his Error. Firſt, a Prince or State that yields to ſuch Councils is a Bankrupt, and, like a broken Citizen, compounds for his Debts at five Shillings in the
<pb n="92" facs="tcp:132772-01:49"/>Pound loſs to his Creditors, and by his or their Proclama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion publiſhes, That all Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors whatſoever ſhall loſe one fourth part of what is juſtly owing them; all Landlords one fourth part of their Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rears of Rent, and all Leaſes for Years to come (to name no more) ſhall loſe one fourth part of their Value; which, as it would be very unrighteous, and a moſt grievous Injuſtice, ſo the Cure which ſuch a Pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctice might be thought to give to the Diſeaſe, would become a much greater Malady, and prove no other than a ſenſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs Chimera and crude Notion in the addle Head of the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jector.</p>
            <pb n="93" facs="tcp:132772-01:49"/>
            <p>Q. <hi>But will not the Publick Stock of Money by ſuch an Act of State be increas'd proportio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nably? And ſhall not we then buy for Nine Pence what before coſt us a Shilling? And, if ſo, is this a ſmall Benefit?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> You are under a miſtake, for your Shillings wou'd 'tis true be twelve Shillings then, for nine there was before; but then you don't reflect that theſe twelve new Shillings will buy no more Bread and Beef in the Market than nine Shillings did when your Money was five and twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty <hi>per Cent.</hi> better; ſo that o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver and above the Folly (not to ſay Iniquity) of ſuch an Act, there are theſe further Evils attending it; as Namely,
<pb n="94" facs="tcp:132772-01:50"/>when your Money is comman<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded to be coin'd, and currant at the rate of one quarter more than it is intrinſically worth, all your Neighbours round a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout you, will Coin and fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſh your Money from abroad, every ill Man will be Coining it at home, and Coin none but legal Money neither, if they pleaſe, becauſe the Profit will be great, without going far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther: While yet, the Tempta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of greater gain would be likely further to prevail, by debaſing your Money yet low<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er and lower, which they may do without much danger of Suſpicion; becauſe when once the publick Money comes to be ſo impoveriſh'd with allay,
<pb n="95" facs="tcp:132772-01:50"/>the Beauty and Complexion of your Coin is loſt, and then an additional Fraud, of three, four or five <hi>per Cent,</hi> is not ſo ea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſily diſcern'd; by which means in proceſs of time, the whole Maſs of National Money, ſhall be in danger of being impoveriſh'd into Counters. Furthermore, all this ſort of Money which you ſhall Coin your ſelves, you ſhall looſe by in the Coinage after the Rate of Five and Twenty <hi>per Cent,</hi> which is eaſie to conceive, by obſerving to you, that the la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour and charge in the Manu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>facturage of your new Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, which is worth but Nine Pence, is equal to that of your old Shilling, which was worth
<pb n="96" facs="tcp:132772-01:51"/>Twelve Pence; ſo that it plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly appears, that one quarter <hi>per Cent.</hi> of the charge of the Coi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nage is thereby loſt: Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore computing your Coinage at the rate only of Two <hi>per Cent.</hi> you will be damnified in the charge of the Manufa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cture, or Re-Coinage of five Millions of Money, the ſum of five and Twenty Thouſand Pounds at leaſt. In ſhort, ſuch a miſtaken Act of Regulation will, in my humble Opinion, amount to little leſs than a Law to make Clipt Money paſs; for it wou'd be tanta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mount: The Species of Gold and Silver wou'd by this means by degrees vaniſh from among us; and what farther miſchiefs
<pb n="97" facs="tcp:132772-01:51"/>to the State ſuch an Act might produce, a little time would tell us.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>One Queſtion begets ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther. You lay a great deal of Streſs I perceive on your No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Intrinſic Value, wherein, (tho' you have already ſpoken to very good purpoſe) yet I muſt pray you to aſſiſt me farther in my Notion of it in our preſent Caſe.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> I would not multiply Words, nor confound you with Terms and abſtracted Noti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons of Intrinſic and Extrinſic, but come briefly to my An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer, which I will now limit to the ſingle <hi>Queſtion</hi> of Money, that being our Theme; pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſuant to which, I reply, That
<pb n="98" facs="tcp:132772-01:52"/>Gold and Silver, for the Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons I have delivered in my general Diſcourſe of Coin, have obtain'd univerſally to be the Matter whereof to make and coin Publick Money; becauſe thoſe two Metals are every where more eſteem'd; and, when faſhion'd into Money, there lying more worth in leſs room than in other Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tals, is thence more adjuſted to the Uſes of Motion and Cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culation; and therefore more proper and aiding towards the Ends of general Commerce; for the ſake whereof, and for no other purpoſe, I conceive it to have been invented and eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſh'd in the World. I ſay, Gold and Silver is all the World
<pb n="99" facs="tcp:132772-01:52"/>over of more value, and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer'd to moſt other things, and Men will give you more in exchange of any other Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modity which ſhall be of grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter bulk, weight, or meaſure than either of theſe two Spe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies contain in themſelves; and if this adds any thing to what I have already ſaid, namely, That whatever has moſt worth lying in leaſt room, will be ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nerally underſtood to be ſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cifically more valuable; then Coin made of Gold and Sil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver, does every where contain moſt Intrinſic Value. Which Repetition perhaps may ſeem ſuperfluous.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>By this Corallary drawn from your general Axiome, that
<pb n="100" facs="tcp:132772-01:53"/>Money now adays muſt have its due Intrinſic Value; I infer, that the more Allay you put into your Coin, or the leſs Gold or Silver it contains, the leſs valuable it will be in the Eye of the World, and that it is not the calling a piece of Money a Shilling by a Proclamation that will work any Effect; but, that if your Coin be made generally baſe or light, it will be rated accordingly; where it will go for no more than what it is intrinſically worth, notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding any Edict to the contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry: For, tho' it is in the Power of the Prince or State, to call a piece of Money a Crown or a Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, and to make it Penal for the Subject to refuſe it for ſuch; yet we may ſafely preſume, that
<pb n="101" facs="tcp:132772-01:53"/>ſuch an Act of State can never be thought to influence the Seller of any Commodity, who will be ſtill left at liberty to vaalue it according to its real worth. Do I conceive you right, or no?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> You do; and the Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon is very plain; for Money is the Rule of Commerce, and Commerce is become univer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſal; but it cannot be a Rule if it be not equally calculated and rectify'd to the Uſe of the general Good; which is the Honour, Profit, Eaſe, and Tran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quillity of the State.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>Explain a little more your meaning, by calling Money the Rule of Commerce.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> 'Tis a Rule, becauſe Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon ſuggeſted and Cuſtom has e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtabliſh'd
<pb n="102" facs="tcp:132772-01:54"/>it ſuch; and, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out this Rule, Trading People would be ever in the dark, and not know how to make one re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gular Step in their Buſineſs, and conſequently, the majority of Mankind would have little or nothing to do without their own Boundaries.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>Open it further, by ſome In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance or other of Fact.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> Let it be thus then: A <hi>Spaniſh</hi> Merchant obſerving here in <hi>England,</hi> that <hi>Colcheſter</hi> Bays are at ſuch a Price, and has a mind to ſend a Parcel in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to <hi>Spain,</hi> where that Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dity is in requeſt; but, that he may be under ſome certainty, he writes to his Correſpondent in that Country, to be inform'd
<pb n="103" facs="tcp:132772-01:54"/>what Price Bays bear there: He tells him, ſo many <hi>Rials</hi> a Piece; the Merchant knows the Intrinſic Value of thoſe <hi>Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>als,</hi> and preſently reckons whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther it will be worth his while to buy Bays here in <hi>England</hi> (as the Price goes) to ſend to <hi>Spain</hi> to be paid for them, as his Factor has inform'd him they will yield. And by this Rule only he is or can be go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vern'd.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>But, do not the</hi> Spaniards <hi>now and then tranſgreſs this Rule, by altering the Price and Value of their Money, and thereby vio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>late this Law of Commerce?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> Yes, I grant they do, to the very great damage of the Trade of that Country, the
<pb n="104" facs="tcp:132772-01:55"/>diſtraction and confuſion of Accompts, and impoveriſhment of the Subject; who by that means, whilſt they furniſh Gold and Silver to all the World, have very little or none Cur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rent among themſelves, and (as I have obſerv'd elſewhere) do manifeſtly owe much of the Miſery they are in to their want of a right underſtanding of this Myſtery; and, were it not for their Mines, and other Profits that ariſe by that Trade, which make ample amends for this unjuſt as well as unwiſe Practice, the Trading World would have no Dealings with them.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>But methinks, after all that you have ſaid, it might be com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſs'd
<pb n="105" facs="tcp:132772-01:55"/>by the Wiſdom of a think<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing well-govern'd People, to make their Money current on what Tearms they pleaſe to decree; which may be done by Enacting good Laws of Aſſize, thereby eſtabliſhing a determin'd Rate or Price on every thing: In which Caſe let your Money be little or great, baſe or fine, it may be made to ſuffice for all your <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſes.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> I grant you would have Reaſon, and might make Nuts and Shells paſs for Money, as they do at this day in ſome Countries, if you were to be ſecluded from the reſt of the World, and would hold no In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tercourſe without your own Frontiers; but, ſince by the
<pb n="106" facs="tcp:132772-01:56"/>corruption of our Manners, Mankind has ſtamp'd this va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue on Gold and Silver, their Uſe is become neceſſary to our Eaſe and Safety, and we can neither gratifie our Paſſions and Appetites, nor defend and ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cure our Peace, Liberty and Poſſeſſions without it; inſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>much that Treaſure of Gold and Silver is become Eſſential to our ſubſiſting and well-be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in the World; and in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gard the only means of ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiring it is by our Induſtry, and the Arts of a wide and univerſal Commerce, we can have recourſe to no other Rule, than by going with the majo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity in the trodden Track of Buſineſs, and buſtle in the
<pb n="107" facs="tcp:132772-01:56"/>World abroad, in order to the acquiring thoſe Things which Cuſtom through Vice and hu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mane Frailty has made neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſary to our temporal Felicity; wherefore your Law of <hi>Aſſize</hi> would here avail little or no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing; while I grant, that in Domeſtick Matters it may be of great Uſe for the caſe of the Poor, and better Being of la<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bouring and induſtrious Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, who muſt labour daily to eat their daily Bread: Here I own indeed, that a judicious Regulation of the Prizes of all Things we conſume within our ſelves of our own growth, would be a means to incourage Induſtry, and tend even to the Advantage of our Commerce abroad.</p>
            <pb n="108" facs="tcp:132772-01:57"/>
            <p>Q. <hi>I think you have made it pretty plain now, that if we would be Rich, Safe, and Happy, we muſt ſwim with the Tide of the World, and ſteer the general Courſe to arrive at the general Haven; and that purſuant to this End, in the Calculations of our Meaſures about Money, we can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not wiſely determine therein, but by borrowing many Arguments from abroad, where our chief In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tercourſe lies, and from whence we derive thoſe means, (for they are not, I perceive, of our own growth) which, humanly ſpeak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, can inſure our Proſperity.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> You conceive me right; wherefore, I think, there will need no more Words on this Point of our Debate.</p>
            <pb n="109" facs="tcp:132772-01:57"/>
            <p>Q. <hi>You told me but now that Money was the Rule of Commerce, which you explain'd well enough; I would now willingly be inform'd by what Rules I may be able to make a judgment of Money it ſelf, or of the value of Gold and Silver, whereof Money is made: For, can Money buy it ſelf, or Gold and Silver be purchas'd with Gold and Silver? This is a little dark to me, and puts me in need of your help to explain.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> My Anſwer to your Queſtion is ſhortly this; That Gold and Silver, which are a Merchandize, the ſame with Silk, Spice, or any other Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>modity which we purchaſe by Traffick, are of late Years grown more ſcarce, either by
<pb n="110" facs="tcp:132772-01:58"/>being apply'd to more Uſes, or that the Circle of their Uſe is become wider; by which means it ſpreads thinner, and the quantity of the Species by that means appears to be leſs, and indeed is ſo, comparing the Uſe that is now made of them with what was practis'd twenty or thirty Years ago: Whence the World wanting Gold and Silver more, they come to be more ſought after, and ſo bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter worth; which is no more than to ſay, That leſs of ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther of them will ſuffice now than in thoſe Days, to purchaſe Labour, Bread, or any other Thing we need and would buy with Gold or Silver. Where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore there is no Impropriety at
<pb n="111" facs="tcp:132772-01:58"/>all in ſaying, That Silver is be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come dear; namely, That an Ounce of that Species, which twenty or thirty Years ago was not worth five Shillings, is now riſen to be valued at a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bove ſix Shillings, becauſe as much Silver as would make five current legal Shillings, according to the Standard of the <hi>Mint</hi> then, ought to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duce by that Proportion ſix ſuch Shillings now. I ſtill uſe whole Numbers, it not being our buſineſs here to inſiſt on rigid Truth of Calculation, but to ſhew barely how every thing is reducible to it.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>Since you have led me thus far in ſearch of this neceſſary Truth, I would willingly be fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther
<pb n="112" facs="tcp:132772-01:59"/>inſtructed by your Reaſons, how, and in what manner (by deſcending to ſome particular Cauſes) this ſcarcity or dearneſs of Gold and Silver is come to paſs in the World; for the true Reaſon being known and conſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to, good uſe, I do not doubt, may be made to the Publick of ſuch Knowledge.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> The Reaſons and Cauſes of this Scarcity I take to be manifold, I will name but a few, and ſhall begin with a main Cauſe; and that is, The long and obſtinate War in <hi>Eu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rope,</hi> whereby, through the Paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion and Ambition of Princes and States, the regular eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſh'd Methods of Buſineſs and Intercourſe of the World is
<pb n="113" facs="tcp:132772-01:59"/>broken. By Sea there is nothing but Violence, Pyracy, and Depra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dation; whereby the Hands of Induſtry are weakned; and that great Channel and Roads of the World's Comerce is poſſeſs'd and beſet by Enemies and Robbers; and we here in <hi>England</hi> chiefly, who pretend to be in our proper Element, who boaſt of Conqueſt and Dominion there, whether by the Violence and good Manage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of our Enemies, or the Drowſineſs or Incapacity, or both, of our own Pylots and Friends at home, whoſe Duty it is to be more on the watch, and to look better out; have receiv'd ſo many deep Wounds in that tender and mortal part of our Body, that it ſeems a Miracle how we ſubſiſt and ſurvive it; while any one,
<pb n="114" facs="tcp:132772-01:60"/>who ſhould preſume to probe and ſearch this Sore to the quick, by nakedly ſtating the Fact in our Maritime Hiſtory and Conduct ſince the War, and tho' it ſhould be never ſo well meant, and merely in order to the Cure of the Malady, he would be thought, I fear, to give too much Anguiſh to be indur'd; and ſuch an Enter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prize (let the Purpoſe be never ſo honeſt and inoffenſive) would taſte too bitter, and look too like a Libel to be ſuffer'd to paſs un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cenſur'd of Authority.</p>
            <p>Thus it is with us by Sea: By Land the War rages more univer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſally, and with greater Violence, tho' not ſo ſenſible to our feeling here in <hi>England,</hi> becauſe our ſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuation has hitherto ſecur'd us from Hoſtilities at our Doors, and
<pb n="115" facs="tcp:132772-01:60"/>our Fields and Farms are not yet forag'd and plunder'd as our Neighbours are; but what we pay, as I may ſay, to be exempted from ſuch Violence, is almoſt tanta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mount, and at a long run will as certainly impoveriſh and undo us: And we may collect from manifold Symptoms, that our De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtiny, without ſome almoſt mira<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culous Means to ſave us, is not far off. Now to give you a Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon how War impoveriſhes the World, becauſe captious and ſceptical Contenders in ſuch Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſputes will be apt to ſay, What do you mean by broaching ſuch Opinions, and maintaining Para<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doxes? Does War annihilate your Money? Is your Gold and Silver diſſolv'd, or gone into the Earth, from whence 'twas taken? This is
<pb n="116" facs="tcp:132772-01:61"/>Malice and Trifling, and nothing elſe. To theſe Gentlemen then, and out of reſpect to Truth and plam Dealing, theſe few follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Reaſons, of the chief Cauſes of Poverty and ſcarcity of Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney by War are tender'd; Let us compute by the groſs, we have ſhewn that Riches are the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duct of Arts and Induſtry; whence is inferr'd, That the greater Num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers there are of Men of Buſineſs and Traffick, Artizans, labouring and induſtrious People, which are the procuring Cauſe of Wealth, the greater will be the Effect. But War is a mortal Foe to Arts and Induſtry, and conſequently produces Effects directly con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary.</p>
            <p>We behold <hi>Europe</hi> at this day ingag'd in a bloody and waſtful
<pb n="117" facs="tcp:132772-01:61"/>War, which, for ought I know to the contrary, imploys a Milli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on in Arms, beſides Horſes and Beaſts of Burden, deſtin'd by Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture's Law to the Uſes of Peace and humane Eaſe, beſides ſome hundreds of thouſands who are exercis'd about Military Matters, as Arms, Ammunition, Stores and Utenſils of War, Fortifications, and the like: All which mighty Numbers of Men and Things, are not only imploy'd in the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fitable Profeſſions of Peace, but are and muſt be ſuſtain'd by pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſe, and paid for out of the Sweat and Induſtry of thoſe that are, who by degrees do not on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly grow too few for the work, but are over and above Sufferers, and moleſted a thouſand ways in their peaceful Methods of Life, as
<pb n="118" facs="tcp:132772-01:62"/>namely, by the Violence, Rapine, Inſolence, and Iniquity of thoſe very People, whom they are ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſtly, with great hardſhip, pain and parcimony, labouring to maintain; till at length they come to cut down the very Bough that bears them, and kill the Tree by whoſe Harbour they were ſhel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tred, and by whoſe Fruit they were fed. Thus the Land comes to mourn and lie waſte, and the Means neceſſary to the Support of great Armies becoming ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hauſted; Oppreſſion, Poverty, and Calamity, inevitably ſucceed. Fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thermore, ſcarcity of Money is begotten in times of Hoſtility, from great Summs falling into Hands where it is under no re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gulation, being prodigally and voluptuouſly imploy'd, ſquan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der'd
<pb n="119" facs="tcp:132772-01:62"/>and ſcatter'd careleſly a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout; by which means it does not circulate ſo currently, and make ſuch regular returns into the Publick Coffers as in times of Peace, when Buſineſs and Traf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fick is contain'd within their pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>per Channels.</p>
            <p>Add to theſe one very great further Cauſe of the decay and ſcarcity of Treaſure; and that is, the Caution and Jealouſie People are put under, every one to ſave his own private Stake. For when Demands of Publick Supplies wax preſſing, and Taxes begin to be felt, 'tis very natural for Men to begin to meditate on Self-preſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vation, to foreſee and provide for the Storm e'er it overtake them: Whence thoſe who beſt can, whoſe Fortunes principally
<pb n="120" facs="tcp:132772-01:63"/>conſiſt in Money and Moveables, withdraw their Effects to Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tries as far as they can from Danger; others hide and conceal by a thouſand Arts every thing that is Money or Moneys-worth, and cover from the World's Eye every appearance of Wealth; profeſs Poverty, and practiſe all the methods of Parcimony ima<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginable, to diſguiſe and ſhelter themſelves from the Jealouſie and Tyranny of Tax-gatherers, and will chuſe to abide the worſt Treatment thoſe cruel Miniſters can inflict, rather than diſcover Money, which they are ſure will yield them Comfort in better Times. And this I know to have been the Practice time out of mind, in the Kingdoms of <hi>Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bary,</hi> where Tyranny reigns with
<pb n="121" facs="tcp:132772-01:63"/>a high Hand, where the leaſt ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpicion of Wealth ſuffices to ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe a Man to the utmoſt Peril; where People therefore live un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der a perpetual Mask, and no Bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy enjoys the leaſt good thing, (whatever he may poſſeſs) but by ſtealth, from which Cauſe (as I have been often aſſur'd from the Natives themſelves) the better half of the Treaſure of thoſe Countries is hid in Holes, and cover'd under Ground: In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſomuch, that it is grown into a habit, even among their Princes, who take a Pride and Pleaſure to bury their Gold. This, I ſay, is another great Cauſe of the ſcar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>city of Money in dangerous and hoſtile Times; and, if we may allow but a fifth or ſixth part of the Treaſure (which would o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwiſe
<pb n="122" facs="tcp:132772-01:64"/>appear among us here on this ſide the <hi>World</hi>) to have been ſo withdrawn and diverted, there would be no doubt but ſuch a diminution would work a good part of the Effect we are ſearching after. To theſe com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon and evident Cauſes of the Evils incident to <hi>War</hi> in general, we may here ſubjoyn why <hi>War</hi> is of late more Burthenſome than heretofore; and that is, by the over-grown Greatneſs of the <hi>French</hi> Monarch, that aſpiring Prince, who would put a Yoak on the neck of <hi>Europe,</hi> conceiving that by the force of an immenſe Treaſure, whereby being inabled to bring greater Bodies of ſtrength into the Field, than was ever be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore practis'd in our Hoſtilities on this ſide the World; he was
<pb n="123" facs="tcp:132772-01:64"/>given to hope perhaps thereby to overwhelm us; which Deſign, though we ſee hitherto to want the effect, we are from thence nevertheleſs inſtructed in the Cauſes of this over-burthenſome warfare, whereby we are put un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der an invincible neceſſity of pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viding an equal Force, which produces an equal Charge to withſtand him, which I thought neceſſary to Note. Laſtly, and over and above the Impediments to our general Commerce, and the Interruption thereby of our general Supplies of what we need, whereby the price of Money is inhanc'd, and every thing comes harder to us. The Mines themſelves of Gold and Silver, I am well aſſur'd are exhauſted, and yield not the Species in ſo great
<pb n="124" facs="tcp:132772-01:65"/>Plenty as heretofore; to which, adding the wide uſe Silver and Gold every day obtains, by ſpreading further into the North, and the Inland Countries: The great Exportations to the <hi>Indies, Turkey,</hi> &amp;c. from whence none returns, muſt to any judicious thinking Man, be concluded to be among the Cauſes of that ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral ſcarcity of Gold and Silver here in <hi>Europe,</hi> in compariſon of what was obſerv'd to circulate amongſt us in Twenty or Thirty Years ago; which has rais'd the value of the Species, and begot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten that difference in price you enquire after.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>You have ſufficiently explain'd the general Cauſes of the decay of Gold and Silver in the World a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>broad,
<pb n="125" facs="tcp:132772-01:65"/>and in groſs, would it be amiſs to bring the Queſtion home, by asking you, how we here in</hi> En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gland <hi>ſeem at leaſt to ſhare a greater degree of the Smart of this Evil than moſt other Nations? Wherefore, if it would not take up too much room, (for I obſerve our Subject begins to run into a longer Argument than I expected) I ſhould be glad you would inſtruct me a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> Your Queſtion is reaſona<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, and I am ready to gratifie you by recounting a few of the many cauſes of this evil felt by us here at home, in a greater Degree of late than ordinary. I ſhall be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gin with Trade, which is a rich, cunning and coy Miſtreſs, muſt have much Art and Addreſs to
<pb n="126" facs="tcp:132772-01:66"/>acquire, and great Attention and Aſſiduity to retain when gotten. This Lady ſeems to have been neglected and ill treated by us of late. We do not, I fear, reflect enough, that her Favors once loſt are hardly recovered, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe we have many Rivals, who are jealous, wiſe and wary, and will be ſure to ſtop the leaſt gap we leave, and hit every blot we make in our Conduct. There are loud Lamentations in our Streets on this ſingle Article of Trade: Let Authority be pleas'd (at whoſe Door it lyes) to lend ſome Attention to theſe Cries, and ſift and ſearch the Cauſes to the Bottom, and they will find Sluts Corners enough. Let them in their Debates and Deliberations, take knowing Men to their Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiſtance,
<pb n="127" facs="tcp:132772-01:66"/>uſing ſuch caution in their Choice; as that when they wou'd penetrate, and cure the E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vils and Errors of one Branch of Commerce, to hear their Reaſons with a more willing Ear, who are ſufferers by ſuch Faults, than thoſe of others who are gainers by them, be their Parts and Ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lents otherwiſe never ſo Superior. For Intereſt is a Paſſion, and Paſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion is both Deaf and Blind. The <hi>Turky</hi>-Merchant exclaims againſt the <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Company, and theſe againſt them, while perhaps both Trades may need Reformation with reſpect to the Publick. The Art is well to diſtinguiſh, for Trade, though it be the publick Miſtreſs, is courted by particulars for pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vate gain, which may, and do of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten interfere with the general
<pb n="128" facs="tcp:132772-01:67"/>good, ſo that there is a leſs My<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtery, and a greater to be diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver'd, for private Men go as much in the dark, and in cuvert to their profit as they can, and to find out and detect theſe bad in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tricate and bye ways, ſeems to be the behoof of thoſe who would go in earneſt upon this work, which requires more Judgment and Pains to execute well, then perhaps is practis'd by our Phy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſicians. In ſhort, 'tis from this great Fountain Trade, that all our Wealth flows: If that be troubled and infected the Streams cannot be pure; every Branch and Channel will gather filth, run thicker and ſlower, and in the end the Stream will ſtand ſtill, and the Circulation ceaſe. But the moſt viſible and grievous
<pb n="129" facs="tcp:132772-01:67"/>Diſeaſe, of which our Commerce languiſhes, ſeems to me to be the heavy Burthens of all Kinds laid on Navigation, which is the ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry bottom on which all our Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſperity is built. Surely we ſhould be more cautious if we conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der'd that we are running a Race with our Rivals in Trade; and a Prize of unſpeakable Value is ſet before us, where he who carries leaſt weight is ſureſt to win the Courſe. Our <hi>New-Market</hi> Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tlemen tell us, That barely an Ounce or two in the weight of a Sett of Horſe-ſhooes ſuffices to loſe the four Mile Courſe: Shall we want the Diſcretion of a <hi>Jocky</hi> in our Deliberations about the moſt ſolemn Thing that belongs to the Government? I could wiſh this Point were better
<pb n="130" facs="tcp:132772-01:68"/>weigh'd that we might diſcern better, and lay it more to Heart, and that our Friends and Neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bours the <hi>Dutch,</hi> might be our Teachers and Examples in the Arts and Wiſdom they Practice, to further Foreign Trade, in the Eaſe and Incouragement they give to Navigation; which being the great Wheel that regulates all the leſſer Movements of the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chine of Buſineſs and Profit; ſhould be watch'd with a wake<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Eye, that nothing might clog or diſturb its Motion.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>While we are on this Article of Trade, I pray inſtruct me a lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle in the Myſtery of Exchange, which ſeems to me to have a great in fluence on Money-Matters; which is the principal Subject of our En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiries.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="131" facs="tcp:132772-01:68"/>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> Your Queſtions grow har<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der and harder, and I honeſtly here own my Ignorance of abun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dance of Arts, or rather Tricks, that are introduc'd and practis'd by crafty Traders in this dark way of Dealing. But thus far I may obſerve, That Exchange is a kind of Uſury, or lending and borrowing Money at Intereſt, wherein Uſance (as they call it) governs, and the <hi>Premium</hi> is pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion'd to the hazard and time of Payment: And, foraſmuch, as Credit (on which this Intercourſe is founded) is a leſs ſolid Securi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty than Land, the Profit thereby does therefore excel that of ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary Uſury. In a word, Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>change is lending and borrowing in one Place to pay and receive in another, and was invented to
<pb n="132" facs="tcp:132772-01:69"/>facilitate the Motion of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merce, but is grown to an Art of ſetting the Dice on Neceſſity, and making every Man fine for his Wants; which is as much as to ſay, That the more theſe Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney-Dealers are let into the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crets of your Streights, the high<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er they will raiſe the Price of your Redemption. Time was when Exchange was regulated here by Publick Authority, and eſtabliſh'd on an exact and ſolemn Scrutiny into the Nature and Value of all Foreign Coin whereſoever we had any Dealings; to the end in exchanging Money for Money, the <hi>Par</hi> (as they call it) being known and adjuſted, (which was the Proportion between the Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue of Sterling and Foreign Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney) they knew to a trifle the
<pb n="133" facs="tcp:132772-01:69"/>comparative Intrinſic Difference of their reſpective Coins, and ſo rated and govern'd their Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>change by that Rule, out of a jealouſie leſt we might part with more of our Bullion for leſs of theirs in this kind of Intercourſe; which, at a long run, might pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judice and exhauſt the capital Stock of Treaſure. But theſe wiſe Cautions are long ſince ceas'd.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>But have not you bin ſilent in one very eſſential Point in the <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſe of this Myſtery of Exchange; as namely, that of being apply'd to even the Scales and Balance the Inequality that ſhall at any time be found betwixt our Importations and Exportations,</hi> &amp;c.</p>
            <pb n="134" facs="tcp:132772-01:70"/>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> 'Tis true; and therefore ſomething ought to be ſaid here on that Subject: Wherein you may be pleas'd to obſerve in few words, that in Trade, when particular Merchants Export more Goods in Value than they Im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>port, or Import more than they Export, the Balance of each Man's Trade is always made up by the help of Exchange; that is, they Lend or Borrow in one place to Receive or Re-pay in another, as I have ſaid. But when a Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion Exports more Goods than Purchaſe the Goods they Import, they Trade to their Gain, and muſt receive in Money what reſts, to balance the Account. When what they Export is not ſufficient ſo to do, they muſt then Pay the Balance, and if there
<pb n="135" facs="tcp:132772-01:70"/>be extraordinary Occaſions to make Payments abroad, that Debt muſt needs be increaſed, and they muſt pay ſo much the more, but which way ſoever the Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lance incline, it is made even by no other way but by Bullion, or by Money by way of Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>change. And this I think may ſuffice for Anſwer to your laſt Quaery.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>What is your Opinion of</hi> Banks?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> I have heard long and intricate Arguments <hi>pro &amp; contra</hi> on this Subject; but as Men for the moſt part contend more for Victory than Truth, I have not bin much Edify'd by eithers Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, as not having not been poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſs'd
<pb n="136" facs="tcp:132772-01:71"/>enough of the merits of the Diſpute; but he ſees leaſt into a Myſtery who is leaſt in the ſecret of the Deſign. In a Popular and new Erected State where the Peoples minds are doubt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful and fluctuating, I think it to be a uſeful Invention; becauſe all who ingage and incorporate in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to ſuch a Community, do in effect give Sureties for their good Behaviour; for in ſuch a caſe Men are ingag'd by ſtronger Bonds than can be had from Conſcience, Religion, Honor, or any other ſpecious Tye; becauſe in theſe we are ſure there may be Hypocriſie, but in <hi>Intereſt</hi> we know there is none. On the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther hand, theſe great and pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick Banks in a State that is tot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tering and in danger, are very Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nicious;
<pb n="137" facs="tcp:132772-01:71"/>for where the Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure is there will be the Power; and in ſuch a caſe if the Bank ſhou'd chance to decline from the Eſtabliſh'd Form of Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, ſo great a weight can hardly fail to turn the Scale.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>Why ſhou'd not a National Bank be always on the ſide of the Eſtabliſh'd Government, is not that their ſafeſt way?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> Becauſe there are mani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fold inſtances of great Evidence, whereby it might be made ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear, that the diſtreſſes of State may inſtil Fears into the Bank Proprietors, that their Money is in Danger, and in ſuch Caſe, they will not incline to favour the State; but becauſe it is with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in
<pb n="138" facs="tcp:132772-01:72"/>in the Memory of Man, that the Bankers and their Creditors were grievous Sufferers by one of thoſe many Caſes incident to ſuch In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtitutions. I will forbear to mention any other, and obſerve only that the Bank then was not a Corporation, had no Conſiſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence or Conſtitution of Strength, to withſtand ſuch Attack; but wherever a body of Men becomes eſtabliſh'd by Publick Authority, ſhall be built on Publick Funds; obtain the ſanction of Laws, to regulate and ſuſtain them, and this Body ſhall come to know its own Strength, to gather and grow Richer and Wiſer in their way, as they will do every Day, more and more: What Seeds of Faction and Sedition may be Sown, and Spring from ſuch an
<pb n="139" facs="tcp:132772-01:72"/>Innovation; what ſtrength of Oppoſition may be form'd againſt the Meaſures the Government may at ſome time or other take in the Regulation or Reforma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Abuſes in the State as may not ſuit with their Ends: In a word, what Influence ſuch a Body of Men may acquire over the Eſtabliſh'd Form of Govern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, who ſhall be back'd with Laws, enrich'd with the colle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctive Treaſure of the Nation, and united by the ſtrongeſt Bonds, ſuperiour to Oaths and Sacra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, <hi>Intereſt.</hi> Of what force ſuch a new Thing may be in an old Monarchy, repugnant every way to the form of the State, methinks a ſhort view with a very little attention may diſcern. Wherefore I will take leave to
<pb n="140" facs="tcp:132772-01:73"/>conclude, That if Monopolies of little Things are declared unlawful by our Statutes, from the Evils that are obſerv'd to grow to the Publick by Tol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lorateing them; then <hi>à Fortiori,</hi> a Monopoly of Money (as 'tis plain ſuch Banks are no other) muſt be ſo with a witneſs. We are told by Claſſic Hiſtory, that the <hi>Bankers</hi> or <hi>Monyers,</hi> (which was one and the ſame thing among the <hi>Romans</hi> in that Age) became ſo Rich and Powerful, and by that means ſo unruly, that the Grievances the State ſuffer'd un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, by the Lycenſe that Body of People (who were Eſtabliſh'd by Authority) had for their Lu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cre and unjuſt Gain introduc'd, coſt no leſs than a Civil War to redreſs; and the Diſpute was
<pb n="141" facs="tcp:132772-01:73"/>long deciding: The Riches and Impudence of the ſeditious Wage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing a doubtful Conteſt with that very Power that ſat them up.</p>
            <p>Such Eſtabliſhments for ought I know, may be ſuitable enough to a Republick, as being in their Nature of a Piece with ſuch Forms of State. And the Hiſtory of the Bank of <hi>Venice</hi> may inform us how far it avail'd there to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards the Fettering of the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, and the eſtabliſhment of that <hi>Ariſtocracy:</hi> But how conſiſtent they are with our ancient <hi>Engliſh</hi> Monarchy methinks there ſhould be ſome reaſon for wiſe Patriots and true <hi>Engliſh</hi> Men to weigh, before we wade too far in ſuch un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>certain Depths.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>I ſee many printed Propoſals of Banks, of a lower Rate; Projects
<pb n="142" facs="tcp:132772-01:74"/>and Funds of Gain and Security,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>to Adventurers, every where pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh'd and preſs'd on the People: What is your Opinion of theſe new Inventions?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> This Propoſition does not ſeem to be within the Circle of our Inquiries, which are calcu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lated for national and general Uſe. But, ſo far as I conceive our Subject and the Publick are concern'd in the Queſtion, I will adventure to ſpeak my Mind, and no further; having nothing to do with the Deſigns and Revela<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions of private Men, who may think they ſee when they Dream, and often, like bold unskilful Py<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lots, carry themſelves and thoſe who truſt them into Perils and Loſs. Tho' for the moſt part ſuch Projects are Snares, being
<pb n="143" facs="tcp:132772-01:74"/>calculated and laid for the certain Gain of the Inventers, and doubt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Emolument of the Adventu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers. Or, if you pleaſe, the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pariſon will beſt hold with the Art of Angling, wherein the cun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ninger the Artiſt is, the more will be his ſucceſs. Now the Bait is Profit, with which he covers his Hook; and, if he would fiſh for Gudgeons, which is a greedy foo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſh Fiſh, it is no matter how bare the Hook lies, ſo the Bait be but alluring: And here let our Artiſt but light on their haunts and he is ſure to have ſport enough. Thus greedy, covetous and weak Men are caught, whoſe Avarice and Hunger after great Gain ſeals their Eyes to the hazard. But, when our Angler would catch ſhy and ſubtil Fiſh, he has recourſe to
<pb n="144" facs="tcp:132772-01:75"/>more ſleights, will fiſh finer, and bait more cunningly, that the Hook may not appear; and often is oblig'd to trouble the Water too, the better to hide his Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe: And this way Men of more Wit and Caution are taken. But here let me be ſo juſt to own, that I am perſuaded there are very ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny well-meaning ingenious Men, whoſe Heads lying this way, do now and then, by long Meditati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on and racking their Brains on one and the ſame Subject, light upon Things laudible enough; but then ſuch Projects are for the moſt part intelligible at firſt ſight, and, like <hi>Columbus</hi>'s Egg, do not need tedious and troubleſome Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plications, through the multipli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>city of Calculation, whereby the Evidence is diſcern'd by but a few,
<pb n="145" facs="tcp:132772-01:75"/>and they ſee but darkly neither: For all Projects are to be ſuſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted of Artifice or Error, where many Queſtions muſt be begg'd; where Contingencies are viſible, and many Caſualties are incident: Which conſiſt of many nice and intricate Parts, that, like many Movements in a Machine, where, upon the failure of the leaſt Wheel, the Motion of the whole is deſtroy'd. A further Objection, for the moſt part, lies againſt theſe kind of Money-Projects; That they are out of the Road and Circle of common Buſineſs; which is very hard to break, and Men of repugnant Methods meet as it were in the dark in their Ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gotiations, and ſo interfere, juſtle, and overturn one another; for, thoſe who would go to their Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by
<pb n="146" facs="tcp:132772-01:76"/>a nearer cut than their Neighbours, muſt leave the trod<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den Path of Buſineſs, where they will either loſe their way, or muſt treſpaſs and do damage to many for the ſake of a few. Further<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>more, all new Inventions of this ſort, wherein Wit and Subtlety go to their Compoſition, over and above the ſuſpicion, the middle Rank of Men (which are the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jority) will and ought to have of their Utility; ſo of courſe the fewer will be found to take part and ingage with them, while the greater and ſtronger Party, not being of their Mind, will become Enemies, and watch perpetually to croſs and perplex them, and combine a thouſand ways to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feat them: And thus their Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſs by that means is in danger
<pb n="147" facs="tcp:132772-01:76"/>of diſappointment. Let me add to theſe Cautions, That I, for my part, take all Projects of this ſort, which are erected on a view of Private Advantage, that are con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceiv'd with much Art, and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire to be manag'd by equal Addreſs, ſeem to me to be little better than Play at Cards or Dice, where Skill and Cunning (which is a ſort of out-witting ones Neighbour) moſtly governs: And as this is but a leſſer degree of Fraud, ſo it often degenerates into rank Cheating; beſides, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing out of the way of that ſim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plicity of Intercourſe, which is in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>telligible and practicable by moſt Men, and by which all Ranks and Capacities of People may be gui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded and better'd by honeſt In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duſtry and Plain-dealing: I have
<pb n="148" facs="tcp:132772-01:77"/>therefore ſingled out theſe few general Objections to ſuch Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jects of Profit, wherein the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick ſeems not only to be nothing at all intereſted, but for the moſt part indanger'd thereby of ſuffer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Damage: I thought it therefore but a little out of my way to in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counter them, and, as I have ſpoken perhaps with more freedom than will be forgiven me by ſome, yet I am perſuaded I ſhall have the majority on my ſide. In a word. I would fain ſee ſome of theſe <hi>ſuperſine</hi> Artiſts ſpin a Web of Uſe and Strength for Publick Wearing; I would ſee Projects for improvement and Encourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of Induſtry and Peopling the Land, which mourns; for introducing and encreaſing ſuch laudable Arts and Manufactures
<pb n="149" facs="tcp:132772-01:77"/>as we have not, and for Refor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation of Abuſes which have crept into thoſe we have; When I ſhall behold Propoſals for alle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viating the unmerciful Burthens laid on Navigation, and tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferring them, if they muſt be born, on ſomething wherein our Wiſdom and good Sence may be better ſeen; which Burthens are as certainly the Bane of Trade and Foreign Commerce, as Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vigation is the Baſis of all our Strength and Riches. When there ſhall be ſound Men fruit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful of Invention of Publick and Popular Minds; who (without driving ſo furiouſly, and hunting with ſo much anxiety after my<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtical Gain, of no kin at all to the Commonwealth,) ſhall tell us how by plain and practicable
<pb n="150" facs="tcp:132772-01:78"/>Methods, we may be rid of the Beggars and Idlers in our Streets; whoſe ſubſiſtance, as it is ſaid to coſt the Nation near a Million a Year, that Summ might not on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly be ſav'd to the Publick, but half as much, for ought I know, gain'd by a wiſe and artful Em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployment of the Labour of that very Poor, whom we now ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtain at ſo very burthenſome an Expence: When ſuch praiſe-worthy Projects as theſe ſhall be ſuggeſted and made Publick, it will be Matter of Joy to every honeſt <hi>Engliſh-man,</hi> and no Ob<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>jection will lie againſt the Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter and Meaning, whateſer may be ſaid to the Form of ſuch Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſals. But let us haſten to our main <hi>Queſtion.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="151" facs="tcp:132772-01:78"/>
            <p>Q. <hi>Let me proſecute my Curioſity then to the Mark we have been all along aiming at; and, according to the Light you have given me into the Subject of Money in general, to ask you, how we ſhall be able to com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſs a juſt Rule for the regulating our Coin here at home, while the Queſtion ſeems, by your way of han<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dling it, to lie ſo deep, and is ſur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rounded with ſo much darkneſs, that we muſt pry into many Myſteries of State, travel into Foreign Trade and Intrigues of Buſineſs to attain a due knowledge therein?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> Perhaps the Queſtion is not ſo hard, as at firſt ſight it may ſeem: This at leaſt I may be ſure of, that ſuch Truths can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not lie very deep, which my
<pb n="152" facs="tcp:132772-01:79"/>weak Forces may ſuffice to draw up. To proceed then, I firſt fix this Maxim, That as your Coin may be too Poor, ſo it may be too Rich, either of which is a Diſeaſe; and is to be underſtood by the Compariſon and Proporti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on it bears, with the matter of Gold and Silver out of which it is made; for we have ſhewn already the Neceſſity we are under, of making our Money ſo as to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain intrinſie value; and being got over that Point, we come now to make an Eſſay, towards determining the Proportion. I ſay then, that Money is poor or baſe Comparatively, as when you make more Shillings out of the ſame quantity of Bullion, by a new Law then was allow'd by your old Eſtabliſhment, for this
<pb n="153" facs="tcp:132772-01:79"/>makes you but nominally the Richer, while Virtually and in Truth, you become poorer by a quarter <hi>per Cent</hi> of the Charge of the Mintage of all the new Money that ſhall be ſo Coined, obſerving the proportion men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned already, and not to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peat the Evils enumerated, this one more we may add; Namely, the Trouble and Moleſtation of Telling, carrying and uſing more Money for leſs Profit than be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, which is ſome clog to Trade, whoſe courſe ſhou'd be made to move with all the Arts of Eaſe, Invention can ſuggeſt. That no Profit can ariſe to the publick any way, by ſuch an E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtabliſhment of our Mint, (where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by your Coin becmes ſo impo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veriſh'd.) We need to go no
<pb n="154" facs="tcp:132772-01:80"/>furhter for a Proof, than the Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervation may be made of what has befallen us by Chance, in our Clipt and bad Coin now grown and eſtabliſh'd by Cuſtom into uſe among us, which hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pening to be diminiſhed to al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt half the Original Value: We behold every thing riſen in Price as it were by that Propor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion; and our Gold Coin which is not ſo lyable to Corruption and Dimunition, riſen from the ſame cauſe near a Third Part, which may ſuffice to ſhew how the publick is affected, when your Coin either by Law or Chance comes to be too Poor.</p>
            <p>Your Coin is too Rich, when a piece of Money, for Example, a Mild Crown ſhall go but for
<pb n="155" facs="tcp:132772-01:80"/>Five Shillings in Money, to buy and go to Market with; when if it were lawful to melt it down and ſell it, for its due worth, wou'd yield you Six Shillings, there being Six Shillings worth of Silver in that Piece. I ſtill uſe round Numbers; the nicety of Calculation not being here neceſſary. Now, as on the one Hand, when your Money is bad and poor, and this becomes eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſh'd by Law or Cuſtom into uſe; every Nation abroad, and every bad Man at home (who has art enough) will be Coining this Money for you, and will im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>part and utter it for your uſe, and their profit, as ſome Nations (which I need not name) ſerve the <hi>Spaniards</hi> at this day, by their baſe black Money, which doth
<pb n="156" facs="tcp:132772-01:81"/>not contain a ſixth part of the value for which it paſſeth with that blind Nation. I ſay by this means, as your Mint ſhall grow out of uſe by the plenty of ſuch Coin as ſhall be Manufactur'd by others to your Hands; ſo your Money ſhall grow worſe and worſe, (for there will be no end of debaſing it) till your whole Maſs of Silver Coin ſhall be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy'd and converted into Traſh and Counters, rather than Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney.</p>
            <p>On the other Hand, when your Money happens to be too Rich, as hath been our Caſe by the great riſing of Bullion in value, ſince the coining of our Mild Money, 'tis plain, and there can be no room for doubt, but that ſuch Coin will be tranſported out of
<pb n="157" facs="tcp:132772-01:81"/>the Land, and by thoſe whoſe pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſion beſt enables them, will be melted down into Bars and Bul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lion, and from this Cauſe, Name<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, its over richneſs or goodneſs this Diſeaſe Springs, and hence is Conſum'd, Vaniſh'd, and Extinct all or the moſt part of the noble Mill'd Coin, which was Minted in the two laſt Reigns; there be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing no Action, how vile ſoever that Gain with Impunity will not Sanctifie, or hardly any Conſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence ſo ſcrupulous, that this Charm has not Power to Quiet and Abſolve; wherefore let thoſe, who by their Occupation have the means of touching moſt Money, conſider and be aware what fort of People this Crime is likely moſt to touch,</p>
            <pb n="158" facs="tcp:132772-01:82"/>
            <p>Q. <hi>If this Doctrine of yours be bottom'd on ſound Reaſon (as it has the appearance) it is viſible that we are led into an Error, by thoſe who would teach us, that the Stan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dard eſtabliſh'd Rule of the</hi> Mint, <hi>(namely, That your Money muſt for ever be juſt ſo fine, and of ſuch a weight) is Sacred, and cannot be alter'd without damage and danger to the State.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> 'Tis ſeen by what has been ſaid, and is, I think, as demon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrable as anv <hi>Problem</hi> in <hi>Geometry,</hi> That the Rules for Coinage, and the Standard of the <hi>Mint,</hi> muſt vary according to the general ſcarcity or abundance of the Spe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies of Gold and Silver; and that 'tis, conſequently, an Error in Fundamentals to hold the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary,
<pb n="159" facs="tcp:132772-01:82"/>as I have endeavour'd to ſhew, and will need no further Explanation here.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>Why (if what you ſay be true) is there ſo much variety in the Coin of Countries, how comes it to paſs that there is ſuch diverſity of coarſe and fine, light and weighty Money in the World? And that all Mankind, who are link'd in one ge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neral League of Intercourſe, do not come to accord in one univerſal Standard for their Money, which would ſave abundance of Trouble in the Courſe of general Traſſick, and ſet the Intercourſe of the World on a much ſurer and eaſier foot?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ. Firſt,</hi> Becauſe Silver and Gold are more or leſs plenty in the diverſe Countries of the World, comparatively, and ſo be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comes more or leſs worth. <hi>Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>condly,</hi>
               <pb n="160" facs="tcp:132772-01:83"/>'Tis hard and hazardous to change any rooted Cuſtom of a Country; eſpecially, in a Caſe of this general Importance, tho' in Speculation it ſhould appear never ſo juſt. <hi>Thirdly,</hi> The Uſe of Money (which was originally invented for the Eaſe and Bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit of Commerce) is become cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupted, and made an Inſtrument of Tyranny and Oppreſſion: The Paſſions of Princes and States, where the Government is abſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lute, making their Power, in this Point of Money, to become a Yoke and a Burthen, which was meant for the Comfort and Eaſe of Mankind; forging Racks and Shackles for the Subject, out of that very Matter, which by Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, the firſt Inſtitution and the right Reaſon of the Thing was
<pb n="161" facs="tcp:132772-01:83"/>decreed, and devis'd for their Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefit and Conſolation.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>You were ſpeaking of Mono<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>polies of Money but now, Do not Princes who enjoy abſolute Power, by this unlimited Authority, make a kind of Monopoly of Money?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> Yes, ſuch Princes can do that by their Power, which a great Bank may compaſs by Art, or come to do by Accident and from the Nature of the Thing: And we know the King of <hi>France</hi> him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, with all his boaſted Wealth, often Practiſes ſuch poor Shifts; proclaiming one Value on his Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney when he has a great Summ to pay, and another when he has much to receive. But the World abroad, by whoſe Sentiments Tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding-People muſt be govern'd, will not heed it; nor are influ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>enc'd
<pb n="162" facs="tcp:132772-01:84"/>by it, and no ſolid Fruit can ever be gather'd from ſuch De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vices, which are ever ſigns of a ſickly Conſtitution; and the Prince or State that uſes them, are like Men whoſe Bodies are de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cay'd by much drinking of Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rits; they are reliev'd indeed in the preſent Pangs they feel, but by the very Draught, which in that Moment yields them Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fort, they are in the end deſtroy'd.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>Why is it call'd the Myſtery of the</hi> Mint, <hi>if our Princes here in</hi> England <hi>make none of thoſe undue <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſes of Coinage, as are in Practice among abſolute States?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Auſ.</hi> Perhaps 'tis continu'd to be call'd a <hi>Myſtery</hi> from the Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er our Princes heretofore claim'd, or had, to make Coinage ſome way or other turn them to Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count,
<pb n="163" facs="tcp:132772-01:84"/>and the Profit ariſing thereby, being kept ſecret, was therefore call'd ſo. Or, it may be ſtil'd a <hi>Myſtery,</hi> from the dif<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficulty moſt Men are under, to conceive and ſee clearly in ſo cloudy and perplext a Subject.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>How long have our Princes been ſo Wiſe, and ſo Good, as to part with a Power which yielded them but a doubtful Profit, at the purchaſe of great Jealouſie of the People, leſt ſuch a Power as look'd a little Arqitrarily, might in time degene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate into Licence, and ſo come to be call'd a Grievance, and the cauſe of Discontents and Murmures, in ſo free and noble a Conſtitution as ours is?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> I think King <hi>Charles</hi> the Second quitted his Right to the Profits accruing by the <hi>Mint,</hi> for
<pb n="162" facs="tcp:132772-01:85"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="163" facs="tcp:132772-01:85"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="164" facs="tcp:132772-01:86"/>ſome valuable Conſideration, which at that time, by reaſon of great Coinage, amounted to thir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty or forty thouſand Pounds <hi>per Annum:</hi> Since when we are, I preſume, at liberty to conſult and determine, by the beſt Rules that Wiſdom and Science can ſuggeſt, about ſuch Laws and Regulati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons for the <hi>Mint,</hi> as may be found moſt eaſie and beneficial for the State.</p>
            <p>Q <hi>How did that Profit ariſe to King</hi> Charles <hi>the Second,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>by the</hi> Mint?</p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> I ſuppoſe diverſe ways, but principally this; namely, that Bullion in thoſe days being much lower in Value than now, becauſe more plentiful, and the Standard Eſtabliſh'd to ſuch a weight and ſineneſs (which was not to be
<pb n="165" facs="tcp:132772-01:86"/>alter'd) a proportional Profit came by that means of courſe to the King through the cheap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs of the Material out of which the Coin was Manufactur'd, in ſo much that the Merchant or Goldſmith had a Merchantable Profit, to incourage them to ſend their Bullion to the Mint, and the King a competent ſhare of Gain in the overplus. But pray note, upon this Queſtion (which helps to unſold the Myſtery) that ſince thoſe days (through the cauſes we have endeavour'd to explain) the Material of your Money is riſen in Value it may be a fifth part at leaſt; and that Batgain which was thought (and it may be really was) ſo profita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble to the King; then ſhou'd his Majeſty have enter'd into Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants
<pb n="166" facs="tcp:132772-01:87"/>with his People to Coin a certain Sum of Money yearly of the Eſtabliſh'd Standard weight and fineneſs (which he cou'd not alter) He might have liv'd to ſee himſelf a great deal more a looſer by ſuch a Contract, then he had been a Gainer; and behold all his Money to vaniſh as faſt as it was Minted, as we have plainly enough ſhewn.</p>
            <p>Queſtion, <hi>I am now at length every way convinc'd, that our Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney ought to be all new Coin'd. And that by reaſon of the new and exor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bitant price of your Bullion, you muſt have a new Standard and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion for your Mint. But how that can be found and ſetled, is a new Queſtion, to which I ſtand in need of your Anſwer?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> We have travel'd a great
<pb n="167" facs="tcp:132772-01:87"/>way to arrive fairly at this ſingle Queſtion; and if we have gone ſomewhat about and made our Journey ſeem longer, then might be thought neceſſary to ſome? I Anſwer, That it was for the ſake of the Majority, that this Voy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>age was taken, and therefore but juſt to go their pace. Our Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject lies in the dark to the Multi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tude, and therefore we cannot open too many Windows to let in the Light, to the end, the weakeſt Sihht may be enabled to diſcern and make ſome Judgment, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by to determine in a matter, that ſo nearly touches every Body.</p>
            <p>Queſtion, <hi>Your Apology is rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonable, and I believe will be thought ſo by moſt Men; but let us come now to an Iſſue, and decide this arduous Queſtion: How, and by what Methods and Rules of Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion
<pb n="168" facs="tcp:132772-01:88"/>our Mint may be Reform'd.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſwer,</hi> I will not trouble you with References to what has been ſaid, that we may not multiply Words, and will take for granted, you bear in Mind that our Hy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>potheſis is fram'd upon Reaſons drawn from abroad, as well as at home; wherefore we muſt take Foreign as well as Domeſtick Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſiderations to our Ayd. Your Money, I have ſhewn is ſubject to theſe two chief Diſeaſes, of being too Rich, which is containing more worth than it goes for in Coin, which begets a Conſumpti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and waſting by re-converting it into Bullion, exporting and the like; too Poor, when it is either Coined by Authority through miſtaken meaſures of State, with too great an extrinſick allowance, or corrupted, clipt and ſalſify'd
<pb n="169" facs="tcp:132772-01:88"/>by others, ſo as to become noto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riouſly diminiſh'd in the intrinſick Value; Which raiſeth the Price of all things by the like proportion; begets doubts Difficulties and Vexa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion in your common Traffick, and enhaunſes the rates of Exchange with your Neighbours, which hath a mighty Influence on your Trade abroad, encourages bad People at home to diminiſh and falſifie it every day more and more, becauſe there is no rule left to compare and know your Money by; And invites the Nations round about you (who may do it with more ſafety) to import and utter it in ſuch quantities, and ſtill worſe and worſe, till in the end, all your Silver Coin, the unclipp'd and the clipp'd ſhall be gone out of the
<pb n="170" facs="tcp:132772-01:89"/>Kingdom; and what a calamitous State ſuch a People muſt be in, needs no Exaggeration here.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>I am glad you have repeated and renewed in my Memory theſe two chief Diſeaſes of Money, and given ſo reaſonable a Prognoſtick of the Effects; becauſe I reckon you will now come to propoſe the remedy for Reſtoring and Eſtabliſhing the Health of our Coin, by ſuch Rules as may ſeem as juſt as your Argument hi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therto has appear'd to me reaſona<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> To arrive then at that right Rule of proportion you require, (and which we have been thus long in queſt of) I firſt propoſe, that we ſhould look a little back here at home, and inquire, and be at a certainty, what Price Bullion
<pb n="171" facs="tcp:132772-01:89"/>bore, when our laſt mill'd Money was coined. And we will ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe it here about the round ſumm of Five Shillings the Ounce, then let us grant it to be riſen and ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vanced in Price, from Five to Six Shillings or thereabouts the Ounce, which ſhall be the Value we will give it at this day: Both which Prizes may be more or leſs, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out damage to our reaſoning a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout the Rule which I wou'd propoſe for our Government in this great Queſtion. Now pray note, that while the King had his Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit by the Mint (which was inde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>finite) and Silver was at an Under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rate no great difficulty cou'd oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cur in the Coinage, for as long as that gain laſted be it little or much, the King had it, who was
<pb n="172" facs="tcp:132772-01:90"/>enabled over and above ſtill to al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low the Merchant or Goldſmith One or more <hi>per Cent</hi> profit, to invite them to bring their Bullion to the Mint; that is, their Silver became ſo much more worth to them when manufactur'd into Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney (which they cou'd preſently utter and employ) than when in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>the Maſſe in their Ware-houſe: Upon which Motive (namely their Gain) they carried it to the Mint. But that incitement ceaſing from the reaſons I have given; there is not only no more Money now coin'd, but even the Mill'd Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, which in thoſe days was min<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted (from the ſame Motive Gain) is melted down again, and recon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verted into Bulloin, as we have noted, and cannot too often re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peat.
<pb n="173" facs="tcp:132772-01:90"/>If this be true, who can with any ſhadow of Rcaſon gain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſay the neceſſity we are under of changing the proportions of our Mint, which muſt inevitably and for ever change; riſe and fall by a Scale of proportion rectify'd to the riſing and falling Value of your Bullion.</p>
            <p>Let it be granted then, that your Silver is riſen in Value from the cauſes which have been enu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merated: We will ſuppoſe here juſt fifteen <hi>per Cent.</hi> ſince your laſt Coinage of mill'd Money; if this be true, then I ſay your Coin at this day, if your Money were tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly minted at that time, (which you are likewiſe to conſider) ought to be juſt fifteen <hi>per Cent.</hi> lighter than that mill'd Money was; for
<pb n="174" facs="tcp:132772-01:91"/>I wou'd by no means propoſe the leaſt alteration in the purity of the Standard; for the many reaſons I have already deliver'd. Wherefore let Authority be pleas'd by the help of Merchants, Goldſmiths, the Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers of the Mint, and by all the cautious and judicious means poſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, compaſs a right knowledge of this Difference (which we do not you ſee here determine) and the Rule for their Guidance in aſſigning, the juſt Proportion to your Coin muſt plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly reſult from thence; as namely, if the Difference of fifteen <hi>per Cent.</hi> here by me propounded were the exact truth, then your new Shilling to be coined, and to be of the ſame fine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs with the old mill'd Shilling, muſt weigh and be worth (within a very ſmall fraction) Ten-pence far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing;
<pb n="175" facs="tcp:132772-01:91"/>I go the plaineſt way to work I can, to make my meaning intelligible to every capacity.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>But methinks by this Rule you are leading into the Error, which you have been all along cautioning us to avoid, for by thus taking from the Subject One Penny Three Farthings out of every Shilling ſeems to me to be very hard, and will for certain be ſo reckon'd by every Body.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> With your pardon, no Body by this Rule, is, or ever can be injur'd; becauſe if People wou'd but open their Eyes, and look with attention, they wou'd Diſcern, that this Ten-pence far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing will buy as much of every thing in the Market now, when your Coin ſhall be rectify'd, as Twelve-pence wou'd have done at
<pb n="176" facs="tcp:132772-01:92"/>that time; which I think may ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fice to ſatisfie your ſcruple.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>What wou'd be the hurt then, if you ſhould make your Shilling yet lighter, provided it keep the fineneſs.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anſ.</hi> Every viſible Departure from this Rule, wou'd prove a proportional damage to the Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject, and have the ſame Effect as in the caſe of clipt money; for your Coin wou'd abate in its E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſteem with the People, in pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion to the Dimunition of its due intrinſick Value; whereby all the Species of things wou'd riſe, and grow dear, accordingly as we find to have come to paſs on the occaſion of our Clipp'd Money; and in ſuch caſe, I grant, the Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jection you have made wou'd a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mount to a Grievance.</p>
            <pb n="177" facs="tcp:132772-01:92"/>
            <p>Q. <hi>But have you not taught that we are not to make our Rule for Regulating the Mint from Obſervations and Reaſons ariſeing barely from among our ſelves here at home, but with regard alſo and reference had to our Neighbours abroad with whom we have Commerce?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> I have and can ſuppoſe the price I have already aſſign'd to Bullion at this Day to be the reſult of a Cal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culation founded on that regard, but becauſe it is neceſſary to explain it I will, as well as I can, why that Cau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion is neceſſary.</p>
            <p>We here in <hi>England</hi> live in the Neighbourhood of divers great Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions who are our Rivals and Vye with us in the Arts of Trade, the <hi>Dutch</hi> eſpecially, who perhaps are Our Superiours in every thing that belongs to that great and profitable Myſtery.
<pb n="178" facs="tcp:132772-01:93"/>They are every way under a bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter Oeconomy and obſerve every thing nearer than we do; they live with greater Frugality, which is their Wiſdom, as enjoying but few neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaries to their ſubſiſtance of their own growth; which habituates them to a narrower Inſpection and Obſerva<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of every the leaſt thing that re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lates to their profit. This penurious Method of Life which in them is a Virtue wou'd not with us, it may be, thought ſo, who live in a wide, rich and plentiful Country, abounding in all things needful to humane life and eaſe. But this greater Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent and Latitude of Life and Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners which we inherit, naturally mol<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lify's us towards Luxury Sloth and Improvidence, and whatever Virtues our good Soil may produce and our
<pb n="179" facs="tcp:132772-01:93"/>better Stars may ſhed towards the exalting our Courage, enlargeing our Generoſity, and forming our minds for Magnanimity and other noble and plauſible Endowments, which I think are more inherent in us than moſt other Nations; theſe native benefits doe, I ſay, beget and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer an incapacity to deal with theſe our Neighbours in thoſe conteſts where Diligence, Penetration, Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gilance and good Husbandry are to be the Weapons. Now Trade which they proſecute more by much for neceſſity then we doe, for they muſt Navigate or Starve, is the Prize held up between us, and I fear 'tis found but too evident to our Coſt, that in this ſtrife the Virtues and Manners which they profeſs are more appropriated to enable them for Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctory
<pb n="180" facs="tcp:132772-01:94"/>than ours. It wou'd be te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dious and perhaps Invidious to e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>numerate by how many Arts they have won upon us of late, but I leave that Speculation to wiſer Heads, and keep within my own Cir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cle which is the ſubject of Money; wherein how far and by how many ſleights they have contributed to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward the preſſures we at this Day are ſinking under on that Score, Prin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted Papers do ſo plainly and honeſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly every day evince that I may ſpare here to explain. It is very likely then (not to ſay very true) that all the Bullion wherewith we aboun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded before this War, and all the Silver that has been clipt from our Money, does this day in a manner Center in <hi>Holland</hi> and thereabouts; this muſt in evitably infer a greater
<pb n="181" facs="tcp:132772-01:94"/>abundance of that Species among 'em and a proportionable ſcarcity with us; that plenty with them muſt needs in ſome degree lower the value of the Species, while this high Tide of Affluence laſts; as it muſt by the ſame Rule inhaunce it here in our low ebb of Poverty. I pray then conſider and weigh with your ut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt attention, how to attain and arrive at ſuch a Proportion in the renevving the Eſtabliſhment of your Mint, that it may not be ſaid Your want of Wiſdom and a thorough Inſight into a Mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter of ſo great Moment ſhall afford them a new handle whereby to hurt you with your new Money. For Example, if you Mint your new Coin with an over-great Extrinſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cal Price, out of an over value and regard to the preſent appearing Rate
<pb n="182" facs="tcp:132772-01:95"/>of Bullion here, which, I note has acquir'd, as I may ſay, an undue and praeter-natural Aſcent in our eſteem; You will thereby be in danger of your Neighbours im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proveing the advantage of their lower price of Bullion to your Detriment, by Importing it to our Mint and purchaſeing therewith; even to the laying up in ſtore for Years to come every Staple Commodity and Manufacture of the Kingdom, by which means whatever preſent appearance there may be of quickneſs of Trade, the conſequence muſt be pernicious; and I will adventure to ſay, that as no People whatſoever can be conceived to contribute a greater ſhare of Blood and Treaſure towards ſupporting the Burthen of the War, ſo
<pb n="183" facs="tcp:132772-01:95"/>none I am ſure even by this ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry means are likely to taſte leſs conſolation from a Peace, whenever it ſhall happen. Which muſt yield but Melancholly Reflections by e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very thoughtful <hi>Engliſh</hi>-man, and therefore one wou'd think ought to awaken us; <hi>leſt we ſleep the ſleep of Death.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Q. <hi>What Method wou'd you adviſe to obviate this Evil, for there is no doubt but our ſuperiours wou'd be glad to turn every Stone to ſettle our Mint on a right bottom.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> You ought I think to begin with this firſt neceſſary Reflection, namely, that this Exorbitant riſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the price of your Bullion, is in a good degree due to the preſent badneſs of your Currant Coin, and the difference in price
<pb n="182" facs="tcp:132772-01:96"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="183" facs="tcp:132772-01:96"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="184" facs="tcp:132772-01:97"/>even betwixt us and <hi>Holland</hi> in like manner to be grown in ſome proportion from the ſame cauſe: Now both theſe Reflections are to bear ſome weight in your Delibera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions, leaſt by over-rateing the cauſes you bend your Argument (which you wou'd ſtreighten) too far the other way. To explain this point a little, you are to reckon that whenever your Coin ſhall come to be better'd (be it more or leſs) the difference or height of Exchange, or of the Price of Silver betwixt you and <hi>Holland</hi> (which is all one) will be leſs of courſe, as from the ſame rec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>koning the value of your own Bullion at home will ſink too. Now I ſay that the Amount of thoſe two, which are but co-inci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent
<pb n="185" facs="tcp:132772-01:97"/>Effects, is to be computed, and by proper helps (I mean ſuch as may be had from Men who are moſt buſied in Trade and Exchange and as ſhall be thought to have Integrity enough to be truſted) an Eſtimate ought to be firſt made, namely, to ſtate to what degree, a little more or leſs, the Exchange with <hi>Holland</hi> and the Price of our Bullion here at home may fall, as a bare and ſim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple effect of the regulating our Mint, without heeding any other matter at all relateing to the ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject. When this Effect, I ſay, which is accidental ſhall be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termin'd, as if it ſhall be deem'd to amount to 3. 4. or five <hi>per Cent,</hi> more or leſs, then this ſum, or difference is to be deducted and
<pb n="186" facs="tcp:132772-01:98"/>left out of the Argument; as namely, if you conclude that this accidental Effect will be 5. <hi>per. Cent,</hi> that your Bullion will fall of courſe on the Re-coining your Money; in ſuch caſe if your Bul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lion be riſen 20 <hi>per Cent.</hi> in the whole you muſt deduct this 5 <hi>per Cent,</hi> out of that difference; becauſe it ought to have no Exi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtence among the ſolid Reaſons for the change you are about to make.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>If I underſtand you right then, I conceive if the appearing difference betwixt the price of Bullion now and heretofore be obſerv'd to amount to</hi> 20 per Cent. <hi>the real difference by your reckoning is but fifteen</hi> per Cent, <hi>and upon that Calculation, your Rule for a new Regulation of the Mint muſt be Built.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="187" facs="tcp:132772-01:98"/>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> You underſtand my mean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing. The next ſtep I wou'd pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe is to conſider, what was the Original Motive of Aſſigning an Extrinſic or Political Value to Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney; I mean that little Value which was given to the publick Coin more then it was really worth, without regard to the ſalſe Reaſons of State that after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards prevail'd, and is at this Day in Practice in Rigid and Violent Governments; and this was plainly for no other End, than to keep every one their own Coin within their own Territory; For while it obtain'd, or there was given 2, or 3, or more <hi>per Cent.</hi> Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trinſical worth by the Mintage, it was ſo much more in eſteem
<pb n="188" facs="tcp:132772-01:99"/>where it was a Native than elſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>where; which was a very rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonable Device to prevent its wan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dring without the Circle of its Currant Virtue. Wherefore let your Coin be Eſtabliſhed with ſuch a proportion of Political Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue as may prevent its going a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>broad, and yet may not be thought to affect you at home in the Prices of the Species of Things, which wou'd amount to an injuſtice and a grie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vance, in proportion to the Er<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rour you ſhall commit; as I have ſhewn. On the other hand, if you make your Money vvith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out any Nominal or Extrinſic ſignification, it vvill (as I have of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten ſaid and prov'd) be the cauſe of your looſing it, by melting down, or going out of the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom,
<pb n="189" facs="tcp:132772-01:99"/>upon the leaſt advance of the price of Bullion, and there is no manner of queſtion to be made but that Material vvill riſe every day more and more as long as the War laſts, from the general cauſes to vvhich I have already aſcrib'd. The grovving ſcarcity of Money in the World, novv as it vvill be very hard to hit a juſt mean proportion betvvixt theſe tvvo, ſo I think 'tis the ſafeſt Errour to incline to the giving your nevv Money too much ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther than too little Extrinſic Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue, becauſe as an Exceſs on that ſide vvill as it vvere ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viate the danger of the riſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Value of your Bullion, ſo the Errour here, vvill affect us leſs than the other way, becauſe
<pb n="190" facs="tcp:132772-01:100"/>money, though a little too poor, is yet better by far than none at all; is much more eaſily melted down and tranſported than it is Coin'd and Counterfeited, the one may be done eaſily by any body, any where; the other can be per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form'd but by a few, and requires great ſecrecy and many Tools; the one is a fault Finable only, the other Puniſh'd with Death, and therefore likely to have fewer Offenders.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>I ſee but one very viſible Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jection to lie againſt this Opinion of yours of giving your Money rather an over than under Exſtrinſic Value, and that is the profit ariſing by the Mintage; for if your new Money ſhall be made to go for ſomething more than it is In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trinſically
<pb n="191" facs="tcp:132772-01:100"/>worth, will there not ariſe a certain profit ſomewhere by the Min<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> Yes, plainly; for if you allot but 5 <hi>per. Cent</hi> Extrinſic Value to your new Coin, the charge of the Manufacturage, which will not be above two <hi>per. Cent,</hi> being dedu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted out of that 5 <hi>per. Cent.</hi> there will ſtill remain 3 <hi>per. Cent</hi> profit; which in the minting of five Mil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lions of Money riſes to 150000 pound.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>Whoſe will this Profit be? for the King you ſay has quitted his right to it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> I am no Judge of that; but if I had the honour of being a Mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber
<pb n="192" facs="tcp:132772-01:101"/>of Parliment, I ſhould wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lingly give my Vote to beſtow it towards a Fund for the new Hoſpital at <hi>Greenwich;</hi> For as no ſort of Men have a greater right to our general Charity then Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, ſo no Charity could riſe ſo eaſily and from ſo publick a Foun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain as this.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>You Determine then, I preſume, that we ought to Re-coin the whole ſtock of National Money;</hi> I do, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe I think there cannot poſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly Occur any miſchief by much ſo grievous and dangerous to the Nation, through any difficulty that may be ſuggeſt'd to ſpring from the new Minting your Money, as thoſe which we ſuffer, and threaten us by delaying it.
<pb n="183" facs="tcp:132772-01:101"/>For the Mint or publick Money is the Pulſe of the Body politick: And <hi>Tacitus</hi> tells us, that the Health and Infirmity of the State was always meaſur'd by that Motion. And grave Authors further aſſure us, That as the <hi>Roman</hi> Empire declin'd, it was manifeſted by their Mint; their Money debaſing, as the Power and Virtue of that great People ſunk and declin'd. Money is the publick Meaſure of every thing we have; all our <hi>Meum</hi> and <hi>Tuum</hi> is weigh'd and diſpens'd by no other Scale or Rule: If that be unequal, falſe or doubtfull, what Injuſtice, what Vexation, Murmurings, Po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verty and Peril, threaten'd the State thereby, needs no Rhetorick to in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>force! Let it be ſeen by the timely Wiſdom of our Remedies, that the Diſeaſe was not Mortal, and the
<pb n="184" facs="tcp:132772-01:102"/>Danger beyond the poſſibility of a Cure: The Calamitous Fire of <hi>London</hi> was a Diſaſter which the World thought wou'd have bin a Death's blow to the State, and, during the Operation of People's Prognoſticks thereupon, brought us very low in our Neighbour's Eyes: But the ſudden Repair of that ſtupendous Loſs, by the Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>building with ſo much Magnifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cence the greateſt City (for ought I know) in the Univerſe, rais'd the Reputation of Our Glory, Courage and Wealth, to a more ſurprizing Degree of Value in the World's, and our own Eſteem too; which by Art, or Wiſdom's Rules, cou'd ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver have bin known or calculated. We may hope for the like fruit from the ſame wiſe and ſteady Counſels: The Calamity of our
<pb n="185" facs="tcp:132772-01:102"/>Coin is not inferiour; the Cure ſeems not, in my poor Judgment, harder; nor will the Benefits which the Nation ſhall reap in the Effect be leſs.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>Have you no further Advice to give, or Cautions to offer, in the main Point of Regulating the new Coinage of Our Money?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> I cannot repeat too often, and therefore once more do re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>commend to your utmoſt Atten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, the deliberating and determi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning the Proportion betwixt the Real and Nominal Value of your Money; which is the Key of the whole Difficulty, and requires the greateſt Advice, Gravity, and Pene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tration to fix.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>Have not you ſaid that the Material of your Money is not likely to grow cheaper, but to riſe ſtill higher
<pb n="186" facs="tcp:132772-01:103"/>and higher; and yet but juſt now you gave me an Inſtance of your fore-ſight that on the Moment your Coin ſhall be regulated, (whether it ſhou'd chance to be rightly or wiſely performed or no,) yet there wou'd preſently, as a pure and ſimple Effect of ſuch a Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formation, be a Fall of the Value of Silver and Gold, and all the Species of things to a Certain degree, the</hi> Quantum <hi>being undetermin'd?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> In this Objection you ſeem not to be aware, that the Abate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the Value of your Silver and Gold you ſpeak of, is no other than an accidental Effect of that Cauſe: But the growing Value of Gold and Silver, whereof I have given you my Prognoſticks is from the general Cauſes already by me produc'd; And therefore this Ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect, by the bye, has no Weight
<pb n="187" facs="tcp:132772-01:103"/>in your Objection, becauſe it will preſently expire, and the general growing Scarcity be no ways in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fluenc'd thereby.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>You ſeem to have yet taken but little notice how our Gold Coin will be affected by the Regulation of our Mint.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> I have already noted, that your Gold muſt neceſſarily fall in its Value upon the Repairing of your Silver Coin, the obvious Rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon of its exorbitant Riſe being from the low Reputation of our Silver-Money; ſo that it has grown higher through the reaſon of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pariſon (as I may ſay) becoming ſo much the more worth from the others happening to fall ſo low, which is therefore owing purely to this unhappy Accident here at home: But of what ill influence
<pb n="188" facs="tcp:132772-01:104"/>it has bin to our Affairs; the uſe our watchfull Neighbours have made thereof, we are loudly and truly every-where told by publick Papers. But a great deal of this Evil, I ſay, will cure of it ſelf, by your Silver Coin recovering its Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>putation: After which, if Gold ſhall be thought ſtill to bear too high a Value, I believe it may be in the Power of the Government to Regulate that at any time by a Proclamation, or ſome wiſe Reſult of Council.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>I think I have now askd you all my Queſtions about the Matter; Let me now ask you a few touching the Manner wherein you wou'd proceed in this great Work.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> I think, according to Advice already publiſh'd, that more Mints than One ought to be employ'd to
<pb n="189" facs="tcp:132772-01:104"/>carry on the buſineſs. And as a foundation to this great Work, I propoſe that One Million at leaſt, or Fifteen Hundred Thouſand Pounds worth of Bullion may be by one means or other compaſs'd to be firſt Coin'd into Shillings and Sixpences, to be a Fund ready prepar'd to pay upon the ſpot for ſuch Clipt Money as ſhall be brought in.</p>
            <p>The next ſtep I would propoſe to be made, ſhould be the Calling in of all the Half-crowns, Thir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenpence-halfpenies, Ninepences, and the reſt of that unequal Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney; your Shillings and Sixpences to remain ſtill currant till this firſt Work ſhall be over. This Money being brought in to the ſeveral Receivers appointed, to be ſpread and diſtributed in the moſt popu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lous
<pb n="190" facs="tcp:132772-01:105"/>Places of the Kingdom, ſhall be paid for in ready new Money by the ſaid Officers; <hi>viz.</hi> Five new Shillings for five Shillings of your clipt Halfcrowns, <hi>&amp;c</hi> receiving all the old Money by Weight as well as Tale, according to the Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thod and Regulation propos'd by Mr. <hi>Lowndes;</hi> for to think of pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing People by piece-meal with Bills or Paper, who ſhall come from far, ſull of Doubts, and pinch'd with Poverty, and vex'd already to the Quick with the Hardſhips they have ſuffer'd, and ſtill lie under; and where the Majority will be found to need every penyworth of the Money they ſhall bring in to be Exchang'd for preſent currant Money: I ſay, to propoſe ſuch a Method as ſhould not be very caſie and intelligible to the greater part
<pb n="191" facs="tcp:132772-01:105"/>of the People, might breed a Miſchief of no verb eaſie Dige<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtion.</p>
            <p>Wherefore I humbly propoſe, that this Million and a half (or whatſoever the Decay of the whole Treaſure of the Nation ſhall be computed to amount to) may be firſt found and provided by ſuch means as to the Wiſdom of the Parliament ſhall appear moſt feaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble; which, in my poor Opinion, will not be an inſuperable Work. This being firſt done, and you be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing then in poſſeſſion of the Bal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lance of this Debt, which is owing to your general Stock of Treaſure, by the Clipping and Impairment it has ſuffer'd; there will remain no other Difficulty but in the Mint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and orderly Diſtributing and Exchanging your Money by ſuch
<pb n="192" facs="tcp:132772-01:106"/>Rules as I think have bin already very prudently and maſterly pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pounded by the ſaid Mr. <hi>Lowndes.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I propoſe your beginning with Halfcrowns, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> becauſe the Work muſt be done <hi>Gradatim,</hi> and can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not be compaſs'd otherwiſe with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out much greater Difficulty and Diſorder; wherein a good deal muſt ſtill happen after all your ut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moſt care to prevent it.</p>
            <p>Your Halfcrowns, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> being re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived and paid for (wherein I note that no Braſs or baſe Money is to be receiv'd,) this is preſently to be Minted up to increaſe your Stock of new Money to be Exchang'd for the old. When this Difficulty is paſs'd, I would humbly propoſe that Proclamation ſhould be made for People to bring in one half or one quarter of their Shillings and
<pb n="193" facs="tcp:132772-01:106"/>Sixpences, or ſuch a proportion as ſhall be Deem'd to amount to the Summ of new Money you ſhall have got Minted. Which propor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Shillings and Sixpences be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing brought in and paid for, (a new Shilling for an old, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>) ſhall be forthwith Coin'd up to produce wherewithall of new Money to carry on your Payments for the old.</p>
            <p>I propoſe this gradual Method in the Coining and Calling in of your Shillings and Sixpences I ſay, to obviate the Trouble, and eaſe you in the many Difficulties which muſt needs otherwiſe occur in the tranſacting ſo voluminous and multifarious a Work. When your firſt proportion of Shillings and Sixpences ſhall be brought in and paid for, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> you are to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed
<pb n="194" facs="tcp:132772-01:107"/>to the next, and ſo on till your Buſineſs ſhall be finiſh'd.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>You have yet made no mention of the remaining Mill'd-Money, and the reſt of the weighty and undefac'd old Coin of the Kingdom; of which ſort there muſt needs be a good quan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tity. What wou'd you propoſe ſhou'd be done with that?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> I propoſe, that whoſoever has bin ſo honeſt as to ſpare from the general Spoil committed on our Coin, or ſo frugal or provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent to have reſerved or laid any part thereof up, that it is but Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice they ſhou'd be conſider'd for the ſame. Wherefore my Advice is, That all ſuch Money ſhou'd be left to the choice of the Owners, whether to Melt it down and ſell it for its real Worth, or to diſpoſe of it to the utmoſt height of its
<pb n="195" facs="tcp:132772-01:107"/>Value to thoſe who may have a mind to buy it, but ſtill to be oblig'd to diſpoſe of it, ſo as that it may be re-converted into Coin.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>Will not bad Men fall to Clip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ping the Clipp'd-money a-new, when it ſhall be publiſh'd by Proclamation, that all the Clipp'd-money is to be paid for on the ſpot with good new<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coin'd legal Money? Or will not thoſe who have cull'd out all the fair Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney from the bad (which is not honeſt) and who by touching a great running Caſh, have it always in their power, will not ſuch Men be able to make a better hand of it by ſending this pick'd Money to the Clippers to be trimm'd, and par'd as cloſe as Knavery and Avarice can ſuggeſt, than by ſelling and re-converting ſuch fair Coin into Bullion, as you propoſe?</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="196" facs="tcp:132772-01:108"/>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> I believe this might be very eaſily prevented, and people wou'd not think of Tranſgreſſing a-new, or of making that undue uſe of their fair Money as you mention, if this ſingle Reſolution ſhall be ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken: Namely,</p>
            <p>That Authority wou'd be pleas'd to direct a judicious Scrutiny to be forthwith made into the loweſt de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clenſion the Coin of the Kingdom is at this day under, and has ſuffer'd by Clipp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ng and Waſting it; and then admitting they find it to be ſunk, for Example, Forty in the Hundred, and that to be the moſt. In ſuch caſe I humbly conceive, that if they ſhall determine that all Money as ſhall be brought to the Receivers to be Exchang'd, which ſhall fall out to be diminiſh'd be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>low that proportion, ſuch Want
<pb n="195" facs="tcp:132772-01:108"/>ſhall be made good by the Bringer or Proprietor, and not by the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick. As on the other hand, all fair Money as ſhall be ſo brought in, that ſhall be found to amount to more than the Value aſſign'd to your new Money; ſuch ſurplus to be accounted for and made good to the Deliverer, as I have propos'd. I know there are ſome Objections ſeem to lie againſt this Expedient; but I am convinc'd too, that the Benefit in the main out-weighs them.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>What ſort of Money wou'd you propoſe to be Coin'd in the Minting your new Money?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> I know Crowns &amp; Halfcrowns are leſs chargeable in the Manufa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cture; but being more liable to Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minution by Drilling, &amp; other Arts, and more coveted by Strangers,
<pb n="198" facs="tcp:132772-01:109"/>and therefore more in danger to be Exported. I ſhou'd therefore prefer the Coining all into Shil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings and Sixpences, with ſome ſmall proportion of leſſer Money. But above all, I humbly propoſe that the whole Maſs of publick Money ſhou'd be re-coin'd and reduc'd to one Faſhion and Manufacture; And wou'd avoid, as a Rock, all new Names and new Values to Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney, tho' I obſerve it to be ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>where propos'd to be done with ſuch old Money as might be thought to remain undiminiſh'd; which they wou'd have ſtamp'd with certain Marks to expreſs its new Value by; I ſay all new Chriſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned Money, and all new Marks to be ſtamp'd on old Money; and all odd, intricate and puzling Va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luations of Money, contain ſo ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny
<pb n="197" facs="tcp:132772-01:109"/>Dangers, Vexations and Diffi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>culties, as I truſt we ſhall take care to avoid by the Self-evidence of the Evils that attend ſuch a Reſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lution.</p>
            <p>Q. <hi>When you have done all you can, and your Money becomes re-eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſh'd to your Wiſh; will it be ever the likelier to remain at home, do you think, tho' we ſhou'd follow in every Article the Rules and Cautions you have propounded to prevent it?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> You have bin told by ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral Treatiſes of Trade lately publiſh'd, that a main Conſideration in the Conduct of our general Commerce, is to avoid, by wiſe and cautious Meaſures, the over-ballance of our Trade. For tho' you ſhou'd have Five thouſand Trading Ships at Sea, and ten times that number of Sea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men employ'd in your Navigati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons,
<pb n="198" facs="tcp:132772-01:110"/>you Trade to loſs, if you buy from abroad, and pay more Money for what you fetch from Foreigners, than you receive from them for your Service, and your own native Fruits and Manufa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctures; with all this ſhew of quick Trade, I ſay, and extent of Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merce, you are blowing a dead Cole, and take all this pains but to diminiſh your Capital or Natio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal Stock of Treaſure: For Trade, without this prime regard, is but little better than Uſury: It may inrich a few ſubtle, buſtling, buſie Men by chance; but the Land will grieve for their gain, and ſuch pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit to particulars will become a Charge on the Debtor-ſide of the publick Leiger-Book, when-ever that Point ſhall come to be narrow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſifted and debated.</p>
            <pb n="199" facs="tcp:132772-01:110"/>
            <p>Now if great Wiſdom and At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tention are due to the keeping this ballance in our hands, and the diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſing it to lean towards our Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit, leſt by inclining never ſo little the other way, it ſhou'd, like a ſlow Feaver, at length conſume us. What Providence in our fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſight, what Talents and reach of Wit, Prudence and Application, may ſuffice to ſave us from the ruine which ſeems to bode us by the exorbitant Over-ballance we behold at this day! Which, like a Comet, threatens the Nation, with this difference only, That we can Calculate to a certain degree, where and how the Malevolence of the One will work, while we can but gueſs at the Effects of the Other.</p>
            <pb n="200" facs="tcp:132772-01:111"/>
            <p>Q. <hi>But ſince this Burthen muſt be bourn, and the bearing of it ſeems the leſſer Evil of the two, becauſe Poverty is ſtill better than Bondage: Me<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thinks we ought to ſet all our Wits on the ſtretch to find Expedients how it may be longeſt ſuſtain'd, and carry'd moſt commodiouſly: For why ſhou'd we want the Diſcretion of a Porter or a Slave; who being condemn'd to bear and carry a certain Weight, will be ſure to diſpoſe of it, ſo as it ſhall leaſt gall and wring his Shoulders. Wherefore if we muſt ſuſtain this Weight, I wou'd be glad to know your Opinion, which is the beſt way to doe it in ſuch manner as not to ſink under it ſo ſuddenly as you ſeem to fear.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>A.</hi> This Queſtion is too bold for Men without Doors to med<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dle in: wherefore I ſhall touch it with the greateſt tenderneſs. You
<pb n="201" facs="tcp:132772-01:111"/>know (for it is no Secret) that there goes out of the Nation at this day a great deal above a Mil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lion yearly in ready Money or Bul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lion, and by what Means this Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney can circulate or return to us again (it being the over-ballance of our Trade, and therefore mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving in foreign Channels) is very hard to Divine.</p>
            <p>Now this great Summ, whether your National Coin be good or bad, muſt go out of the Kingdom, if this over-ballance muſt be paid; And therefore if you have no Bul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lion, you muſt ſend Money, where your extrinſical Value will not be underſtood, and where your Clipt Shilling, which paſſes for a Shilling here, ſhall go for no more than it weights; and therefore there muſt go a great deal more to pay a fo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reign
<pb n="202" facs="tcp:132772-01:112"/>Debt, than would ſuffice to pay the ſame Debt here at Home.</p>
            <p>Wherefore if a Million of this Money, which by the urgency and fatality of this deſtructive War goes yearly out of the Kingdom, were in another manner employ'd; as, namely, to maintain a ſo much greater Maritime Strength of our own as may amount to that Summ; and by thus eaſing our Neighbours of juſt ſo much in their Naval Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pence, which they might transfer and employ to the ſame Uſes for which our Money is at this day Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted into <hi>Holland:</hi> I ſay, if ſuch a Project were feaſible, the Benefits to us wou'd be unſpeakable, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of that I may Enumerate a few: Firſt, this great Summ wou'd then Circulate within Our ſelves. Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>condly, Our Naval Strength wou'd
<pb n="203" facs="tcp:132772-01:112"/>be augmented by a third part more than it is at this Day; whereby our Line of Battel would be ſtronger by the Union and Conſiſtence of our own Native Strength, and we ſhould have to ſpare to cover our Commerce from that Deſolation that has hitherto afflicted us; and by ſecuring eſpecially our Plantati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on-trade, which is our Mines of Gold and Silver, we ſhou'd taſte the relief which that Trade wou'd afford us to our much greater pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit. Thirdly, Trade, which now languiſhes and is at deaths-door, wou'd by this means revive among us; ſo many more hands wou'd be ſet a work in every Profeſſion, and ſo many Species of things of our own growth wou'd be utter'd and ſpent, that I am perſwaded if ſuch a difficulty cou'd be overcome, it
<pb n="204" facs="tcp:132772-01:113"/>wou'd give a new and cheerfull face to our Affairs here at home at leaſt. Laſtly, by thus encreaſing our Mari<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>time, which is our Native Strength, we ſhall ſhine brighter in our own Orb, and grow ſtronger, as reſting more on our proper Center. We ſhall encreaſe our Strength by borrow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing no body from their peacefull Trades and Buſineſs, but employ ſuch, as when the War ſhall beended, will be ſtill in their Element and Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſion, where our wide Commerce ſhall with open Arms be ever ready to embrace, cheriſh and employ, to the Nations beſt and ſureſt Intereſt.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>I am, <hi>YOUR LORDSHIPS Moſt Humble Servant,</hi> &amp;c.</signed> 
               <dateline>
                  <date>Decemb. 1. 1695.</date>
               </dateline>
            </closer>
            <pb facs="tcp:132772-01:113"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
